<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="assets/styles/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Diary of April Rivenend</title>
  <subtitle>A technology focused blog about hate, love, the ugly and the catch in the fine print. All from personal experience.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/" />
  <updated>2025-08-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name>April Rivenend</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Super self-conscious about my friends count.</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/conscious-friend-count/" />
    <updated>2025-08-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/conscious-friend-count/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;SpaceHey is a platform that can be hard for a lot to navigate, especially for somebody who might have migrated from other places. I&#39;m one of those people, using SpaceHey as a sort of &quot;alternative social media&quot; that I&#39;ve been using more than anything I used to use. And with that, comes, well,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of care for my own friendship count, for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it came to &quot;moots&quot; culture, I was always out of place. I didn&#39;t care about my follower count, usually I held Mutuals with people I already talk to (even a little), and I generally just didn&#39;t attention seek. When I was on Twitter, my one and only goal was simply, just post what I was thinking of that day, as intended previously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But then I made the move to SpaceHey and it&#39;s like I now self-impose my own limits. Always keep the friends list ONLY full of people I care about, continually remove people who go inactive or I never get anything back from (or find bulletins to read/interact), make an effort to add specifically people I would want to actually talk to and get to know... That kind of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know, it&#39;s kind of weird that I&#39;ve just suddenly started caring a lot about friend counts and what friendships I hold when a couple of years ago, I just made effortless friendships with people, even if there was just one hobby we were doing together and I didn&#39;t know ANYTHING else about any other interests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do I just care about the details too much now? Do I pay attention too much to people? I don&#39;t know, am I just an extrovert wrapped in social anxiety, and the &quot;introvert&quot; label I have is just... irrelevant? All of those times I thought I was a genuine introvert were just total bullshit? I&#39;m super social with people I know, but I don&#39;t like big groups. Fuck, what the fuck am I??&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do I care so much about who I add on SpaceHey..???&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Preserving your own history is important!</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/preserve-your-history/" />
    <updated>2025-08-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/preserve-your-history/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;PRESERVE YOUR HISTORY, PEOPLE!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since 2020, I was always peculiar about how I handle my history. Previous chats, screenshots, past Minecraft worlds... I just want to preserve all of it. I care a lot about how I archived my things, because you never know if it&#39;ll all up and vanish one day! I&#39;ve had so many Discord accounts that I&#39;ve gone through, some accounts just straight up deleted because I was super paranoid, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Tyrrrz/DiscordChatExporter&quot;&gt;Discord Chat Exporter&lt;/a&gt; has since become a very important part of my personal arsenal of tools. It&#39;s so important!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just love having a personal library of stuff I can browse, because I can just go through everything on my own time. With my drive dying in June, I can&#39;t really do that easily anymore, but I&#39;ve tried my best to back everything up that I want the most, so hopefully things stay smooth sailing!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Leaving (most) modern social media for SpaceHey</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/spacehey-retrospective/" />
    <updated>2025-08-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/spacehey-retrospective/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;5 years ago when I was 14, I was on quite a few social media platforms used by majorites. TikTok, Discord, Twitter, Tumblr... You can name it! Over the years I&#39;ve come and gone in many places, some more places I&#39;ve been to being Instagram (which i am never touching again, unless if you put a gun to my head or really forced my hand), Snapchat (the worst message platform i&#39;ve used, ever), Bluesky, Skype, Mastodon...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been to many places when it comes to Social Media. And now, the only three important places I can be found on is SpaceHey, Discord, Neocities, kind of GitHub and sorta Reddit. A lot changes, doesn&#39;t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience with SpaceHey in general has kind of been over the place. I&#39;ve met genuinely wonderful people on here (with &lt;em&gt;varying&lt;/em&gt; backgrounds) and have a few times made lasting friendships that are still going today. That&#39;s great, but how did we get here, where it&#39;s practically the only active place I&#39;m on, other than Discord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This assumes a lot that Discord is not a &amp;quot;social media&amp;quot;. I&#39;ve quite many social media platforms, but Discord is technically the only &amp;quot;major&amp;quot; example (excluding YouTube, which I don&#39;t think counts) of a social platform run by big tech that I actually use day-to-day. Twitter is toxic, Instagram is toxic, TikTok is toxic, Tumblr is toxic &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; has crazy people stories, Snapchat is mostly used by people in my schools that I don&#39;t connect with...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discord is another one of those &amp;quot;toxic&amp;quot; platforms in nature, and I couldn&#39;t ever really blame anybody for hating Discord. It&#39;s a source of hell for a lot of people and generally just run by idiots who want to add nothing but monetization and monetization to the platform. But, it&#39;s also the fact that it&#39;s the only real platform I can get a bunch of friends on. It&#39;s a place that I check often and have on all my devices, has a bunch of features I want, good modding... And so, I check it a bit more than SpaceHey, because it has other social features I really like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of thing has basically become another &amp;quot;social pressure&amp;quot; situation where I can&#39;t really &amp;quot;migrate&amp;quot; to a Discord alternative, but really, there&#39;s no other good alternatives, lol. Guilded is run by ROBLOX, Revolt has no rich presence at all, NO platform has implemented Discord&#39;s Rich Presence system, a lot of games already lack Rich Presence, I&#39;m not using TeamSpeak if I have to pay a host to run me a server... etc, etc, etc. Discord just &amp;quot;works&amp;quot; and that&#39;s all I&#39;m going to use for a while. Sorry to those who can survive off just SpaceHey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right, the topic. I&#39;m throwing Discord out there because it&#39;s basically the only &amp;quot;modern&amp;quot; social media I&#39;ve fit into. I hate everything else, mainly because either I&#39;m never seen or I just so strongly hate the userbases to the point that I&#39;d rather avoid the entire thing like the plague to get away from all the people who write a bunch of annoying, negative comments. Tiktok and YouTube are nothing but spam. By the time I started settling and getting used to SpaceHey&#39;s slow pace, I&#39;ve practically thrown everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because SpaceHey actually makes me feel seen. If I had to list problems with a lot of social media platforms, it probably has to go like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TikTok is used by so many diverse people, but nobody I actually want to interact with. Its algorithms pushes stuff to me pretty much days after it passed, the comment section is full of kids doing comment manipulation junk that makes you think there&#39;s a hair on the screen, fake like button, etc. Also, 50% of the time, the &amp;quot;nerds&amp;quot; in the comments are misinformed and run on ages old advice. And also, attention span, I want mine back, thank you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube needs its comments completely stripped, its CEO changed and its AI moderation completely removed. And also, a couple of notable figures on YouTube right now need to be taken out back... to a nice dinner with a spam bot, so we can stop hearing about all the drama.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discord is overmonetized and is a tag team haven for youth harm along with ROBLOX, but unlike ROBLOX, Discord is an essential part of my social interactions right now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter was ALWAYS toxic and Bluesky has practically outclassed it by now. Only reason you need Twitter still is for following companies, but I&#39;d rather use XCancel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tumblr&#39;s underground communities are a horror and share a lot of red flags with a very miniscule % of SpaceHey&#39;s userbase. The clean side of Tumblr is mostly boring or just memes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram is as bad as TikTok. If not, worse. The only time I seriously used Instagram was for DMs, but even then I still dislike it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snapchat was mostly used by the people in my school, and has earned the reputation from me for being the app that the popular kids and &amp;quot;trend follower&amp;quot; users use. Sorry for viewing you so low, Snap. I like my chat history when it SAVES without me forcing it to every message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bluesky is Twitter but predominately LGBTQ audiences. AKA, Twitter without the right wing hate; overly political and sometimes with some cool artists worth commissioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastodon is just Fediverse Bluesky, and was practically made redundant when Bsky came along.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skype is dead and was always buggy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;yeah... I have a lot of things to say about modern social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t really fit into these social platforms, because I&#39;m just very stingy with interactions. A lot of the time, the interactions on these platforms don&#39;t matter to me. I don&#39;t care at all about followers, or becoming trending, or really anything, but I know a lot of people who do, whether to trend follow and fit in with the userbase mould or not. If anything, it seems most of my friends use them and struggle to get on SpaceHey at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SpaceHey came along and practically just completely fucking changed how I view Social Media and how I use it. When I was starting to pick up SpaceHey and adapt to its pace, I was using Blip to post my thoughts (as opposed to bsky) and also semi-active on a few alternatives to try and stay active on the internet. By the time I got to here and started &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; kicking off my interest in writing blogs, I basically abandoned everything and used purely just SpaceHey in terms of social media (apart from Reddit, where I used to search for Minecraft ads).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is pretty much the only social platform I really turn to, to read posts and post comments on. Everything else kind of just sucks. And since then, SpaceHey entirely changed how I angle Social Media. Who knows what is next.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I joined an SMP a couple of days ago, and since yesterday, this random shack has just been on my property.</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/the-smp-shacker/" />
    <updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/the-smp-shacker/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post should have a bit of silly context, especially because this is just a longer form of the bulletin I just made! If you looked at &lt;a href=&quot;https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/&quot;&gt;my NeoCities page&lt;/a&gt; (which has a brand new button btw! please replace it people), you would have saw that on August 9th, I joined a bunch of SMPs and got accepted! For convenience, let&#39;s call the Minecraft SMP this happened on, &amp;quot;Retro SMP&amp;quot;. That&#39;s far from an accurate name. I don&#39;t care. Privacy needs a shitty name replacement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So on Retro, I picked a spot on a hill. Placed my bed and chest, the basics, and settled off for the night. I was dizzy the night I logged on, so I was kind of out of it and just wanted to get my bed sorted out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go to bed and don&#39;t log back in until yesterday afternoon, to find out some dude built a shack on my hill, left his stuff in a chest and put a sign in front of my spawn point basically saying &amp;quot;Hey! There&#39;s a shack on your right if you want to use it!&amp;quot;.&lt;br&gt;
THIS MAN. BUILT A LITERAL SHACK ON MY LAND. AND JUST GAVE IT AWAY???&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He didn&#39;t even take his stuff back. I put signs back because I just want him to pick up all of his shit from his chest because I don&#39;t want to take his shit, and there&#39;s been no response for like a day. The dude&#39;s definitely logged in since then. I think he forgot he built this beautiful little shack at all. Like...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is some CRAZY lore. Who just casually builds a shack on your lawn???&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I struggle with friendships and socializing, so here&#39;s a vent about it.</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/friends-rant/" />
    <updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/friends-rant/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As somebody who is usually a shut-in and just doesn&#39;t speak to people much without slowly warming the dial. As a result, most of my interactions with potential future friends tend to mostly be about a bit of yapping back and forth in hopes it snowballs into a state where I can yap on my own and randomly pop in without thinking about the awkward part about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That has worked for many friendships I&#39;ve made over SpaceHey; just exchanging a long conversation first thing about interests. When my go-to idea is to leave a nice and long profile comment after getting my friend request accepted and (god forgive) I get a nice yap back with some answers, sometimes that&#39;s all the spark I need to start a nice conversation over SpaceHey. And then the chances of possibly unadding the other person after the first week are reduced by maybe 25%, assuming they don&#39;t randomly go offline forever afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does that have to do with this topic, though? That&#39;s because in the past 2-3 months alone, I&#39;ve either not gotten anything out of doing that or just get demotivated halfway through writing the comment, because of other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I generally try to avoid vent posts and purely avoid ranting unless if I can add a comical or informational hint to it, because if I was just to rant angrily like &amp;quot;I hate my life, nothing comes together&amp;quot; without a takeaway, it would just feel like a vent. So when I talk about rants and when I actually write rants, it always has a takeaway.&lt;br&gt;
i.e: If I&#39;m ranting about OptiFine, I&#39;m going to also talk about the downsides with unbiased information. (&amp;quot;You literally cannot even step forward, because of the lag. That&#39;s right, this increases the LAG.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;small&gt;this is not an example. optifine doesn&#39;t actually do this. i just needed something that sounded like what im talking abt, sorry&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this time, this is different. I just need to talk real for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genuinely, I don&#39;t know how I made it through ANY of my teen years. When I turned fresh 13 in 2019, I was mostly in Roleplay spaces and was mostly celebrating the fact my ROBLOX account was now free from the underage filter. The games I played then mostly consisted of Hmm (that meme game where you open doors), RoCitizens and maybe if you were lucky, After The Flash. How I was social then was literally miracles, because I could confidently start RPs with people and type &amp;quot;abc&amp;quot; in the chat without a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that worked. That built up some friend groups I visited a lot, got me in a lot of fun roleplays that I even hold on to this day, got me in places I felt I was safe in, helped me develop my characters... I kept remembering names, kept roleplaying to keep my happy up, and while I was a troublesome teen and a bit of a nightmare to deal with on the family end, I kept pushing. And I was having fun and making memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it was easier to be social then because I actually grinded my ass off to be part of a community I liked. I put my all into people, met a whole wide range of people with varying amounts of passion for Roleplay, sometimes got to do things with them outside of Roleplay... I was a social butterfly. Speaking up for myself was easy, it was easy to defend myself or speak out against others because I was confident. I was not as introverted as I had become later on, and wasn&#39;t aware of the internet&#39;s true horrors yet to care. I actually put effort into approaching people. I fit in because that&#39;s just how I was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Times have changed so fucking fast. I have to bring that up and bring up all this history because we need to also look at right now: a complete mess. In 2025 alone (6 years since my &amp;quot;prime&amp;quot;), everything is just all fallen apart. 90% of friends I&#39;ve made then have changed in one way or another, and I get some of them, but others are ridiculous. I knew a few people that became TikTok induced maniacs, or became problematic in ways that I didn&#39;t align with. Also met people who seemingly changed for the better, yet the friends they talk to are rude and I cannot stand them. Sometimes, it isn&#39;t even their fault. Sometimes our interests just align so little after they quit RP, that the only real tie we had left was basically cut. Because that&#39;s all I usually did with partners, just roleplay my ass out if I could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept in contact with about one person from back then, and even they&#39;ve turned into a ghost. They&#39;ve been struggling mentally, been in a shittier place in the house than I ever could, they&#39;ve become old enough that they could even be working a job while they&#39;re off. They&#39;re the only person I&#39;ve trusted, aligned with and genuinely related to strongly enough that I didn&#39;t drift from them. And yet, they&#39;re struggling and M.I.A. in what I could consider the &amp;quot;worst&amp;quot; part of my life. I fucking owe them an apology for being a turd when I was 13, if anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at how that&#39;s changed, a lot has changed since my social prime in 2019. Compared to then, I hesitate to reach out first when I add people over SpaceHey. Sometimes even if I get the confidence to do so, sometimes small talk or other &amp;quot;hi! how&#39;s that project you&#39;re working&amp;quot; small sentence stuff, just doesn&#39;t click. When I&#39;ve made friendships, usually it was after a length profile comment reply to a profile comment I wrote. That was usually the best case scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&#39;t entirely about SpaceHey, of course. Just a small example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s also Roleplay. Since I was stalked and defaced in 2023, I&#39;m scared to step in Roleplay environments without the irrational fear that maybe, that same man would be in the crowd. Even if I&#39;m in a game I KNOW he wouldn&#39;t know about, I feel out of place. I have to spend about 5 minutes pondering if it&#39;s worth it to reply &amp;quot;abc&amp;quot; to start a roleplay (if you&#39;re lucky to find one of those now, which could be it&#39;s own post), and by the time I&#39;ve taken the risk, they&#39;re gone. Sometimes, even making decisions like that gives me a mini panic attack. Like my heart gets a little uncomfortable when I try to socialize like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just don&#39;t know how I&#39;ve even made friendships at all! It seems total luck based, and it doesn&#39;t help my case that I&#39;m pretty much a glass cannon when it comes to socializing first. I might one day take that risk and go first, by pure luck, but sometimes when I do, nothing comes of it. And then I just wait for the next opportunity to do it all again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I genuinely CANNOT grasp how I survived my teen years making the friends I did through 2019-2022, because everybody then might as well have been problematic OTHER THAN the single person I met then. And even THEN, I don&#39;t know how to make friendships now. I am literally socially outcasting myself by doing this, and I continue to do it??? My newest friendships have been literal magic and everytime I make a new friend, there&#39;s always that subtle reminder that something is coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My longterm IRL friendships have already broken off because I&#39;m very reactive and emotional about what I work on. There&#39;s no saying when somebody else is going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I probably also dug my own grave here by being so picky. I&#39;ve become so used to meeting either dry people or just so ready to prepare for almost no chemistry, that I&#39;ve literally been letting that bias control what friend requests I accept or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahhh, there&#39;s so much to unpack. I&#39;ve gone from being a social butterfly to a literal fool. This is my first time coming out about this, because I&#39;m generally opposed to making vents and actual rants. I don&#39;t like doing it, I&#39;ve been uncomfortable binge reading vents and rants before. But this time, I think I need to let this go.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sodium was the best thing to happen to Minecraft since The Aether</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/sodium-retrospective/" />
    <updated>2025-08-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/sodium-retrospective/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sorry for the weird, inaccurate, possibly clickbaity title... It was between &amp;quot;The Aether&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;OptiFine&amp;quot;, and saying OptiFine was a good thing to happen to the Minecraft community gives it too much credit. This post is a bit of a buffer between my last few posts and any future posts, because I&#39;ve been struggling to write anything big. This post is just a little small, bite sized thing to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My take might be a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; self-indulgent, especially because I thought the best fitting title was &amp;quot;best thing since The Aether&amp;quot;, which is a bit of an over reach... But I promise this is meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll just put my take on the table right here and just say right off the bat that Sodium is a &lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; advancement in modding. No really, the take is about Sodium&#39;s advancements in the performance scene!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OptiFine back in the beta days was &lt;em&gt;kind of&lt;/em&gt; effective and was definitely very new, having come right out of early 2011 and was created around the early stages of Minecraft&#39;s beta stage. The game has been out of Alpha for a few months and was starting to slowly round out into something that would eventually make the building blocks for what the game is today. Well, what the game was before 1.9...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point is, it was around for years, from 2011 all the way through &lt;em&gt;ALL&lt;/em&gt; the early and mid game releases. It chugged through the famous 1.8 that minigame servers use today, through the combat update, 1.12&#39;s changes, the aquatic update and the changes to villages, and through every update after, despite having not really getting anything more significant or better optimizing since about 1.8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then Sodium popped up during the Nether update (Sodium v0.1.0) and practically threw OptiFine out of the window for people who &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; used it for performance. Since then, Sodium is in version 0.6.13 and the advancements this mod made lead to a Forge focused port, native NeoForge support for Sodium, Sodium being integrated into clients all around, an introduction to many people for the power of what Modding really does...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sodium kind of just changed the dynamic of everything. OptiFine, a tool many people had used &amp;quot;just to run the game better&amp;quot;, was practically now behind as Sodium rushed to get ahead of the scene. For some people on exotic configs, maybe they didn&#39;t feel it, but for a majority of people like myself who make an effort to tweak settings and dig around, yeah, it makes a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not sure how to put into words just how to say Sodium improved a lot of game performance to me. There&#39;s a lot of complications, such as some systems not exactly having the best drivers or being too outdated to benefit from Sodium, the type of version you choose to game on, what other mods you pair with it, but as a baseline, Sodium had pretty much become an essential. OptiFine had just become a tool for older versions. Sodium kind of outdid any use I had for OptiFine, and while I don&#39;t use Shaders due to how fast they cook my computer, Iris basically already deals with that scenario too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know if there&#39;s much else to say. Sodium is just a miracle for optimization, and ever mod that follow suite since then, including many modern essential mods have just made a better, stronger standard that OptiFine ever was.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>OptiFine is not your savior - a retrospective &amp; PSA on how optimizing Minecraft has changed</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/optifine-psa/" />
    <updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/optifine-psa/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In progress since &lt;code&gt;7/26/25 3:44 PM&lt;/code&gt;. Original idea from &lt;code&gt;7/18/25&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Introducing...&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minecraft is one of those games that I will always have a love-hate relationship with. The experience of modding either ends in love and two hours of love and power as I play with crazy cool improvements&lt;br&gt;
...or I&#39;m spending the next hour removing mods one by one and reading game logs to figure out what went wrong. Only for it to be something trivial, stupid, or well, I give up on the spot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everybody gets to share that sentiment. People prefer Client Launchers that just open the game, apply a few optimizations and the fun is over. While &lt;a href=&quot;https://rentry.co/mclients&quot;&gt;I have some issues with that&lt;/a&gt;, it&#39;s not hurting anybody. People have many reasons to not care about playing, including time and effort, but some just have super rigs with good temps and can afford to undercut.&lt;br&gt;
Of course, that&#39;s a terrible way of looking at it, but people are people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can also get people who just can&#39;t wrap their heads around the optimization space. And of course, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TheUsefulLists/UsefulMods&quot;&gt;several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DJSng106/toolkit&quot;&gt;lists&lt;/a&gt; exist to help with that! Well, as best they can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, there&#39;s just so much I&#39;d love to talk about when it comes to modding. There&#39;s so many good posts, a lot of rants that would be fun to share my experiences with, as well as just generally reminding people that modern Minecraft has a lot of new performance advancements!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then... There&#39;s that thing. In the title.&lt;br&gt;
I fear it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;OptiFine.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either I just pissed off a good few people, became the fourteen hundred thousandth person to rant about it, or just said what everybody knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A quick &amp;quot;hello&amp;quot;!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s nonsense, of course. I never even told you about the man of the hour! Let me introduce you to this man before I yap your ear off about his warcrimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OptiFine is a Minecraft tweak created by sp614x around the time of Minecraft&#39;s Beta 1.2 days, originally created as two mods. It started in 2011 as a silly, simple project about Minecraft and optimizating the game, before the main developer would decline giving their code to Mojang roughly around 2013,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;OptiMine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first was OptiMine, which seemed to have started around Beta 1.2 (released Janurary 2011) and was created by a different person named Scaevolus. It was about rewriting the text engine to support Unicode (although fonts not included), Fast Render, and other general optimizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s last update was during Beta 1.3_01.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;OptiFog&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second was OptiFog, a predecessor to OptiFine released for Beta 1.4 (March 2011, the day before April Fools!). It was mostly about removing Fog, but also had some basic optimizations such as &amp;quot;FPS Boost&amp;quot;, Occlusion Culling, and chunkloading optimizations in it&#39;s first ever version. Later versions would add MCPatcher, OptiMine &amp;amp; Modloader support, and some other familiar options that would make it to Minecraft later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s last version was during Beta 1.7.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;OptiFine: Merging the two Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, you probably got &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; bored listening to all that yap. Long story short, the two projects, as well as another mod project merged into OptiFine for beta 1.7.3, and the rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s fine, that seemed to be the end of the post, right? Most people probably walked out on the history yap, thinking this is just a post full of slop, yeah? This is just a lame talk that&#39;s clickbait about how OptiFine is popular?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, you didn&#39;t even let me to get to that part!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Welcome to 2025.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minecraft is a game that, while not seemingly so, has many issues with Performance. Maybe one day, I&#39;ll make a post about Sodium. Maybe a post about modloaders, or even about 1.21.5... Yikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the meantime, we need to talk about OptiFine. Specifically, modern version of OptiFine. Yeah, mind fucking, I know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I get the argument on legacy versions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me just first off say that this isn&#39;t about &amp;quot;OptiFine&amp;quot; being the devil and that you need to quit it NOW for this alternative version. The truth is, there&#39;s not always an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On versions like 1.8, 1.0 and even the beta builds, you just have to suck it up and use OptiFine. 1.7 has Angelica and anything after 1.14 has Sodium, but for everything in between, you&#39;re just plain hosed. OptiFine is really your only choice right now. And last I checked, Legacy Fabric doesn&#39;t have anything solid to replace it. Or a Sinytra Connector clone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for a version like a beta, or maybe a very early release version, I get it. The mod support for early versions is very dry now that 2011 is a decade past and we&#39;ve moved on to newer versions. Yet, I just wish there was a way to backport the OptiFine competitor out of spite... Embeddium&#39;s done it, Rubidium&#39;s done it, Angelica&#39;s done it, but I still don&#39;t get how 1.8 doesn&#39;t have an Angelica-like mod yet. Why does 1.7 need the special treatment, because they have GregTech? 1.8 needs it for competition! It&#39;s a very popular version for PvP and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry, just very passionate about Minecraft. The modding scene is a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; bizzare, and since 1.20 ages, modders have struggled to keep up. Some mods are approaching a year since their last update :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it&#39;s just... we could use so many better choices. OptiFine did it&#39;s job in what, 2014? Back when the optimizations were still fresh and actually relevant, compared to today, where they&#39;re just super old and only do the &lt;strong&gt;bare minimum&lt;/strong&gt; for performance now. It&#39;s just...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The version racism is stupid.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, titlecard. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modding&#39;s racism is so dumb. First of all, OptiFine &lt;em&gt;itself&lt;/em&gt; has done so, skipping 1.21.5 themselves, so they&#39;re definitely guilty of it. 1.21.6+ is available but under pre-release status[^1], etc. So before you put this on modders, don&#39;t forget that your savior has also sinned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second of all, the modding space has &lt;em&gt;ALWAYS&lt;/em&gt; been hostile. 1.7 being the only pre-1.15 version to get any kind of Sodium resembling overhaul is already ridiculous, let alone 1.8-1.14 having to just &amp;quot;make do&amp;quot; by themselves. I know that 1.9 is very unpopular, and 1.8 is mostly just Hypixel players that already use Lunar for performance, but come the fuck on, people!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was also &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; going to happen, considering the modding space is also full of a lot of conflicting opinions. You have mod authors that haven&#39;t updated in almost a year and seemingly have gone missing, dead, or possibly demotivated to update mods you really want, picking the right version, deciding between Forge and NeoForge for 1.20+, if Forge has all the ports you want...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like holy shit, was it not enough OptiFine was replaced since 1.15? Did we need to also over complicate everything? This is not a modding issue &lt;em&gt;in its entirety&lt;/em&gt;, but it&#39;s still an issue some authors fuel. God...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Things have changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But some things are meant to change. That&#39;s why we have Sodium to replace it. That&#39;s why every modder warns you to avoid OptiFine like the plague on every version past 1.14. That&#39;s why modders gravitate towards Fabric. That&#39;s why I always tell my friends to use Fabric over Forge. Because times have changed, and all the good things are currently on Fabric. Either the people porting to Forge have specific versions in mind, or are only going for the low hanging fruit: the most popular choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s just all very hostile. So hostile, in fact, that Lunar Client has chosen steal[^2] Sodium for themselves! The CaffeineMC team has made a mod so good at outdoing OptiFine, that clients are starting to use it over OptiFine. Talk about funny?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry, that was my victory lap. I just find it funny they&#39;ve already jumped ship. After all, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20230421115716/https://rentry.co/silvermcsetup&quot;&gt;I&#39;ve already complained about them being inefficient&lt;/a&gt;, I guess they have to one up that by taking what was a modder exclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;There&#39;s better options&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, listen. I know, I&#39;m dogging on OptiFine &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; hard. You&#39;re probably either really sick of the yap, or you just want me to hurry up and recommend an alternative. I got you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, get &lt;a href=&quot;https://modrinth.com/app&quot;&gt;Modrinth&#39;s launcher&lt;/a&gt; for Minecraft. If you have never modded before, Prism Launcher looks too bloated and you&#39;re too tired to learn anything else, Modrinth is easy, updates your mods to the latest version for you, and does what it&#39;s meant to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the mods. The launcher won&#39;t do the magic on it&#39;s own. That&#39;s tiresome, I know, but we have lists for that! Try picking up &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DJSng106/toolkit/&quot;&gt;Toolkit&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TheUsefulLists/UsefulMods&quot;&gt;TheUsefulLists&lt;/a&gt;. Find the version you want to play on, browse the list, and install whatever mods show up for your version. Profit, and you&#39;re de-fined! If you miss shaders, just install Iris and be on your way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connected textures? Continuity. There&#39;s also some mods for many features OptiFine had! &lt;a href=&quot;https://optifine.alternatives.lambdaurora.dev/&quot;&gt;See here&lt;/a&gt; for more options!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this kind of thing might not encourage &lt;em&gt;everybody&lt;/em&gt;, but I&#39;m just saying that the option is out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&#39;t a faster rendering engine better than an all in one modpack that was last performing at its peak in 2012?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a bit of a hard yap... Maybe I&#39;ll follow this up another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[^1]: Last checked on July 27th 2025. By the time this blog is finished, it&#39;s probably already out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[^2]: No really, they did. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lunarclient.com/news/patch-notes-21/&quot;&gt;https://www.lunarclient.com/news/patch-notes-21&lt;/a&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Picking Sides - Minecraft&#39;s Modding Problem</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/minecraft-modding-racism-problem/" />
    <updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/minecraft-modding-racism-problem/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It might seem very self explanatory if I ever just opened a post with &amp;quot;Minecraft is a game&amp;quot;, so instead, let&#39;s say Minecraft is a very popular game with a lot of modding potential, but also a lot of modding problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s a good opener, right? Is that how you open a successful blog?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, it&#39;s total luck based?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Another case of love and hate&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as I dog on Minecraft&#39;s modding hostility, it&#39;s really a love circle to get to play a game that&#39;s had so many cool mods. While that &lt;em&gt;doesn&#39;t&lt;/em&gt; include a lot of the tech and magic mods people like, such as Create&#39;s complicated systems (which I can&#39;t wrap my head around, I already barely wrap my head around the base game), all the tech heavy modpacks and other total tech overhauls, but I always appreciate all the work people do on the Optimization front to make it barely work, and such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just can&#39;t believe how bad it gets sometimes. People picking fights with specific versions, different modloaders having different mods, people being selective of when they port mods and what loaders they develop for... etc, etc. This was likely a problem Forge created by not innovating much, yeah, but then Fabric became what Forge was. A lack of innovation. NeoForge came along to innovate, but right now, Fabric is still worth it over NF because it still has more mods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the cycle keeps getting fed because developers prefer Fabric over anything. I can understand prioritizing a modloader for personal reasons, such as literally being unable to keep up with Mojang&#39;s shit ON TOP of other modloaders (which by the way, is a very common thing!), but preferring it because you just have a stigma against everything else sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because instead of empowering new things that could become the norm and even fix what was wrong with what we already had, you instead made me rely on a connector and cross compatibility layer that barely even works. It was so bad, I ended up just moving a modpack for a group of friends from NeoForge, allll the way back to Fabric. Because it runs like ass, people pick too many sides, and my own personal experiences with both have made me land on Fabric. Because there&#39;s more optimizations and stuff tailored to what &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; personally want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah, if you say &amp;quot;yeah, well I already struggled modding modern Minecraft, so I mod on 1.xx.xx so I can have so and so&amp;quot;, congratulations, &lt;a href=&quot;https://harveysorts.bearblog.dev/posts/2025/optifine-psa/&quot;&gt;that&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://harveysorts.bearblog.dev/posts/2025/specialk-and-minecraft/&quot;&gt;one more&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://harveysorts.bearblog.dev/posts/2025/minecraft-buddies-rant-v2/&quot;&gt;feeding&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://harveysorts.bearblog.dev/posts/2024/my-browser-history/&quot;&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://harveysorts.bearblog.dev/posts/2024/the-server-hunting-problem/&quot;&gt;slippery slope&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
Oh, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instructables.com/Modding-Minecraft-the-Easy-Way-for-windows/&quot;&gt;you&#39;re&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minecraftforum.net/forums/mapping-and-modding-java-edition/minecraft-mods/1275355-1-7-3-aether-collaboration-mod-v1-02-new-mobs&quot;&gt;wrong&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Nobody gets it&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s put aside version wars for a minute. Let&#39;s &lt;em&gt;try&lt;/em&gt; to listen to the people, as somebody who just wants to play vanilla with friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, sure, 1.12 is popular. I&#39;ve known many people who would point at 1.12 and say &amp;quot;1.12 was the peak modding and doesn&#39;t have these problems&amp;quot;. Okay, sure, let&#39;s rely on OptiFine instead of Sodium and see if I either max out my CPU or get lower than Modern (which already should be comfortably low compared to everything else!!!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, well it&#39;s very unlikely it would perform worse than Modern, so let&#39;s claim it&#39;s on par, which is &amp;quot;perfect&amp;quot; for our case! Cool, the game still runs, that&#39;s all we need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, now make it connect to 1.16+. Do not use ViaVersion. Do not use ViaBackwards. Hard assume that I am physically incapable of doing anything on the server, and make the solution entirely client-sided.&lt;br&gt;
Let me put you in a clearer challenge. You likely thought I was kidding and said &amp;quot;Well, you don&#39;t&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make it connect to all the server versions that modern SMPs use, which are all servers I mainly play on, where many people will also be present with me. That means all of 1.20, all of 1.21, maybe even 1.16-1.19 too. Throw in 1.12 for safe measure too, just for the 1.12 purists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah, &lt;a href=&quot;https://modrinth.com/mod/sodium&quot;&gt;go&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://modrinth.com/mod/starlight&quot;&gt;ahead&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://modrinth.com/mod/chatpatches&quot;&gt;and&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://modrinth.com/mod/recursiveresources&quot;&gt;also&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://modrinth.com/mod/chatnotify&quot;&gt;port&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://modrinth.com/mod/jade&quot;&gt;every&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://modrinth.com/mod/notes&quot;&gt;mod&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://modrinth.com/mod/packed-packs&quot;&gt;I&#39;m&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://modrinth.com/mod/quick-menu&quot;&gt;accustomed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://modrinth.com/mod/skinshuffle&quot;&gt;to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://modrinth.com/mod/viafabricplus&quot;&gt;playing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://modrinth.com/mod/vtdownloader&quot;&gt;around&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://modrinth.com/mod/presence-footsteps&quot;&gt;with&lt;/a&gt;. Prepare for every edge case while you&#39;re at it. Go right ahead, I will be here waiting when you figure out how to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go ahead and also figure out every crash. If it crashes when I touch it, do not send me anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Racism everywhere&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That probably sounded &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; cruel. And you&#39;re right! That was very demanding, but the problem is that&#39;s just how I play. I play mostly Vanilla and play with a lot of assistive resources. A lot of random seeming mods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Version racism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And nobody seems to get that down. In a place where the alternative is to starve, I&#39;d rather deal with Modern Minecraft&#39;s bullshit than cut a few things, because those &amp;quot;few things&amp;quot; has become everything I look forward to when modding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that was a fight between downgrading to 1.21.1 and starving. I chose to starve myself of a few 1.21.1 exclusives. Namely, Cull Less Leaves, Tips (by Darkhax), and a couple of other &amp;quot;livable&amp;quot; mods I might last a few months without. x.7 is missing a bit more, including Roughly Enough Items... But it is what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God, I just hate modding. Everybody has a version preference and it&#39;s plain racism. 1.21.5 made horrible rendering changes that people skipped because of, and even &lt;em&gt;performance mod authors&lt;/em&gt; are making 1.21.5 exclusives to combat the fact that so many people hate working on 1.21.5 as it is right now. God...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minecraft&#39;s version space is a nightmare. There are mods that just pick sides because it&#39;s a modder&#39;s favorite version. There&#39;s 1.21.1 of course for many people, there&#39;s also been 1.20.1, 1.18.2, 1.16.5... God, we&#39;re already tangling ourselves into an ugly little mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s just so much selectism for specific versions, I don&#39;t like it. We&#39;re all picking sides and-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Loader racism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, fucking knew that was coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it&#39;s not a version exclusive thing. That should have become VERY obvious if you know what Fabric is. I&#39;m not even going to touch how LuxForge and NeoForge are two separate things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, many beginner modders only develop on Fabric. Almost everybody only develops on Fabric today, and that has basically turned the space into a capitalism ring. Fabric rakes in all the mods on latest versions while Forge users either have to starve or switch over. Hell, sometimes you even have to consider going to Forge or starving because some of your fun stuff is on Forge. Then you have to do it again, because, surprise, Origins is unstable and &lt;em&gt;abandoned&lt;/em&gt; on Forge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, does that mean either of them are better than the other? No lol, Fabric gets beef from veterans who can&#39;t let go of Forge, Forge itself is dead since 1.21.2 because everybody&#39;s porting to Neoforge, hell Neoforge is unoptimized at times...&lt;br&gt;
I could go on. Not to mention, some people will prioritize Forge on other versions. Wonder why Legacy Fabric is unheard of and obscure? That&#39;s why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The racism is also on the older versions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think what some people fail to realize is that this isn&#39;t like, a modern thing. I actually notice this is a &lt;em&gt;retro&lt;/em&gt; thing too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like for example, before 1.16. Sodium 1.15 is pretty much fictional, and everything before it is just nothing. 1.12 doesn&#39;t have a port either, so you have to use the inferior choice to play at all. Oh, and the million other optimizations that are hostile to each other, that too. A system that was &lt;strong&gt;already&lt;/strong&gt; basically perfected in modern versions, where the same few optimizations basically work together in harmony and don&#39;t actually &lt;strong&gt;conflict&lt;/strong&gt; with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry, is that too hostile? I&#39;d like you to also fix 1.8, for those who play on PvP servers. OptiFine is far too little choice!!! And don&#39;t forget my 1.12 ports!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My Point -- 1.12 isn&#39;t a &amp;quot;kill all&amp;quot; bullet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of yap for something I could summarize in short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty much, I find people overpraise these versions. It doesn&#39;t actually help. 1.12 might solve the problem of mods not being present on newer versions, and you could in theory give up joining any modern SMP to use it, but then you have new problems; crashing galore! And a bunch of other problems that aren&#39;t coming to mind right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that&#39;s not the juice of this rant. I just wanted to get the fun one out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The slow update cycle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank Mojang for all of your problems. Game drops!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting since roughly 1.20 (and debatably 1.21, to an extent), there has been a huge shift in how mods are handled. Updates are slow now, some mods not having been updated in months, sometimes spanning over at least a year. Their last supported version? Usually a 1.2X.1 version of some kind. ALWAYS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of this is mostly the fault of Mojang&#39;s &amp;quot;Game drops&amp;quot; update, which practically forced modders to work at a break-neck pace. Now, obviously that&#39;ll create problems. It&#39;s a sure fire way to get demotivated on a project!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then that also leaves me to have to deal with being anxious about when the modder can keep up and update while I&#39;m on this latest version, before a new version comes out and fucks everything up, and by the time I&#39;ve updated...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THE NEW UPDATE CAME OUT. AND ALL THE FUCKING SERVERS UPDATED TO IT. EVERY ONE!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I absolutely &lt;strong&gt;despise&lt;/strong&gt; working with Minecraft modding because of this one, simple phenomena. A new version comes out and EVERYBODY moves to it, even if all of the fun mods like Presence Footsteps and such haven&#39;t caught up. So while everybody&#39;s having fun on 1.21.12 or whatever the fuck they&#39;re playing, I have to stay back on 1.21.1, &lt;strong&gt;still&lt;/strong&gt; waiting for the updates to come to at least 1.21.10!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like, this is fucking madness! Do people NOT get tired of working with this? Everything&#39;s so hard because your work can be obsoleted in a tap. Just one flick, you have to update and nothing is updated yet. Please, just either make a replacement that works on the current version, or please just fucking update your shit. Please...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLEASE!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My take on SpaceHey being &quot;dead&quot; (as somebody who is active on both SpaceHey and modern socials)</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/spacehey-dead-take/" />
    <updated>2025-07-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/spacehey-dead-take/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I initially joined SpaceHey in 2023 and was on and off since 2023 due to a variety of reasons, such as losing interest (expecting overstimulating first interactions, believing myself the site is dead, etc) and generally just being too lazy to log onto a site I felt I wasn&#39;t benefitting from. I thought I would give my own take on SpaceHey being &amp;quot;dead&amp;quot;, as somebody who is between the &amp;quot;fast&amp;quot; social media (specifically Discord. I am also a former TikTok user) and SpaceHey&#39;s oldschool approach to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cycle for new users, unfortunately, is inevitable at this point. You probably know what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see new blog posts every once and a while about people remembering to log in after months, new users who sometimes end up not replying to me and disappearing the week after, etc. That cycle of &amp;quot;make account, spice it up, add a few people, get bored and leave&amp;quot; is going to be inevitable, because SpaceHey changes how people view social media. If you were a TikTok user and expect to drown in attention on every post, obviously Spacehey is going to bore you. SpaceHey is not the kind of site where you could make a post and get a lot of attention, it took time for me to accept that too, but I don&#39;t make posts expecting attentions anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do end up getting a lot of hanging friend requests to people that have never logged on in a while, too. I&#39;ve recalled some friend requests I sent after finding out somebody last logged on two months ago, and my friend request was also almost two months ago. I do also get the perspectives of people who end up getting bored, because in a way, I&#39;m also bored. My main type of communication has always been Discord, which is a &amp;quot;fast&amp;quot; paced platform for most, and sometimes that doesn&#39;t make some people comfortable, as Discord is also the place where a lot of bad things have happened for some people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But unfortunately, SpaceHey is just the second place I go to. If you&#39;ve only ever &lt;em&gt;been&lt;/em&gt; a SpaceHey user and have avoided ever other social media &lt;em&gt;perfectly&lt;/em&gt;, you probably don&#39;t get it. But for myself, I&#39;ll sometimes log into SpaceHey, be thrown off by the slow pace, and just believe the site is dead because nothing comes to me. Keep in mind that I struggle to start friendships with people, so that part isn&#39;t just a SpaceHey problem. SpaceHey made it easier to become friends with people, definitely, unlike modern social media, I can actually approach people, and on the off chance, actually connect with people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But every once and a while, nothing. I&#39;ll be unable to take the slow pace and I&#39;ll dip early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, that&#39;s ironic, considering I&#39;m active on a social media platform mainly meant for active messaging, with colored status indicators and all, but that&#39;s just what it is. I joined Discord (first as an underage in 2017, then properly) in 2019, and for my entire teenhood, that&#39;s just been the standard for me. And it remained the standard for 4 years until I joined SpaceHey, of course SpaceHey was going to look like alien magic. Plus, TikTok had me ensared in 2020 before I started going on and off since 2022, then dark in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s just that it&#39;s a time thing. On some days, of course, I like SpaceHey&#39;s slower vibe. I would post a blog and be okay with the slow pace, completely fine with how slow everything happens, and that just gives me the time and energy to surf through profiles in post. A lot of times, however, I just step away early and check back later, expecting a notification to await me. It&#39;s mostly a dopamine thing.&lt;br&gt;
Plus, searching for things is tedious. I write blogs, research is already tedious. Searching for things to reply to and do is even worse with somebody of my attention span.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get both sides, especially people who say that the people say that SpaceHey is &amp;quot;dead&amp;quot; are just not trying hard enough, because I do see it! Blogs get made, people actually respond to you, some people log on frequently enough to be even somewhat active, and there&#39;s still a sense of community, even if said community is arguing with each other. Though, I still resonate with the impatient kids, because SpaceHey in general is slow. Not everybody has the patience for that. That pisses off people who have the patience, sure, but everybody&#39;s going to be different in the end. You can&#39;t just put every person on the world on a hot spice and expect everybody to like it... :P&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Minecraft and Special-K is undocumented, unaccounted, unsupported (or so it seems)</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/specialk-minecraft/" />
    <updated>2025-07-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/specialk-minecraft/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey look, it&#39;s the first ever post on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://aprilhvs.bearblog.dev/&quot;&gt;new blog website&lt;/a&gt;! I would have kept using Zonelets, but the RSS support kind of sucks, so...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a quick mention that I&#39;m using Bear Blog now! They have an ATOM feed, that while does not preserve the original publication date, lets me show off the history of &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of my blog posts! The RSS happily seems to work, and possibly also &lt;em&gt;sort of&lt;/em&gt; preserving the publication dates, but it&#39;s only the first few entries. That&#39;s completely fair, I used ZoneRSS and after my feed reached maybe a couple of thousand kilobytes, it just gave up entirely trying to work. Oh well, we have a solution, and it might be off platform, it&#39;s great!&lt;br&gt;
And plus, for the SpaceHey readers, I can still mirror my blog to you guys just fine. Hello, all of my friends!!! Are you subscribed? I&#39;m curious!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very quick disclaimer that this post is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; talking about the Kelogg cereal, as funny as that would be. This is about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.special-k.info/&quot;&gt;modding application&lt;/a&gt; by (who I think is named) Kaldaien.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Hell: A Love / Hate Relationship&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right, the post. Thanks, titlecard.&lt;br&gt;
If you&#39;re unaware: Minecraft modding is hell. You probably need some context before we talk about Special K.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my very basic understanding to crash logs, to performance mods all being split up willy nilly, right to all the incompatibility, hellscapes, the various clients that claim to be mod compatible but aren&#39;t, the beginners who stick with these clients because of their convenience, the modders like myself who are either on a high horse or wanting to bank on a new investment...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not a surprise it&#39;s hell. Like, it&#39;s not a surprise at all, but that&#39;s what comes with experience. Of course, when you remember that Mod Z and Mod Q are incompatible, you get magic, and sometimes that magic is much better than something like Lunar Client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Love - A Drug&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take for example, my friend Rosalynn&lt;a href=&quot;https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/specialk-minecraft/%5Bhttps:/spacehey.com/profile&quot;&gt;^1&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, some people can&#39;t easily try new things and need either a lot of help, somebody to set it up for them, or even every feature they used re-added. So, after a while of thinking about it, one night I convinced them with all my heart that I wouldn&#39;t download all of their bank details after we installed an alternative for Teamviewer, I set up their first modding launcher, set up their first modded instance, set up their first vanilla instance...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And one two three, bam, we&#39;re done. After installing some resource packs and shaders, making sure the shaders do not microwave the CPU, and waiting a while for a glass connector mod that hadn&#39;t yet updated to the version I based the instance on, it was all set up. She got to experience the fun of Jade (WAILA fork), Xaero&#39;s Minimaps (and waypoints! :D), the Origins mod, browsing shader packs in-game, Sodium&#39;s benefits over OptiFine, and all of the other beautiful advancements made in the performance section of the Minecraft community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And well, that was only made pretty because of Mods. And even though Lunar tried to take the spotlight, there was still plenty of mods that Lunar couldn&#39;t impliment even if they tried to appeal to me. Stuff like Jade, waypoints, fullbright, Sodium, Zoomify, ViaFabricPlus (an amazing multiconnect fork), Freecam, and so many more opened doors... Lunar might be able to do it some way or another, but the mods will always do it with less bloat on the client. And that&#39;s what matters. The best experience possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And through Rosalynn&#39;s wonderful patience, I opened the door to show her all the new cool things to come through. And together, that night, we tried so much crazy bullshit. And we were happy, making memories, like all good friends do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry, got a little caught up there. Point is, modding&#39;s good. As much as I hate it, I can&#39;t do anything without it, and that&#39;s the love part of my love-hate relationship with mods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hate - A Motivator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The devil exists! How delightful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modding is also a switchblade. It plays nice when you use the right cards, but sometimes you play a card a little too early, and it&#39;s a kick in the weak point. Whether that be emotional damage, or something a bit more &lt;em&gt;extreme&lt;/em&gt;. Like, &amp;quot;losing dark souls again for the millionth time&amp;quot; extreme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.12, if you haven&#39;t tried it before, is a nightmare to optimize. Of course, 1.12 was released in 2017 and that was around during the last time that OptiFine was effective, so you could &lt;em&gt;probably&lt;/em&gt; still survive off OptiFine. but for somebody like myself who want to get a tiny bit more out of everything, there&#39;s quite literally a mod named &lt;em&gt;LoliASM&lt;/em&gt; (which had to be censored when it went to Curseforge) among all things, Cullers, OptiFine, a bunch of other stuff... And then you add everything and realize the amount of incompatibilities just fucks with your brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think it will be an issue for most since you most likely &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; use OptiFine anyway, so nothing changes for the majority, but for those few nuts, that sucks, because you want to get the most out of Minecraft, and you can&#39;t D:&lt;br&gt;
Because everything FUCKING CONFLICTS!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Come in, Special K!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, there&#39;s our star.&lt;br&gt;
History lesson, time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special K (seemingly named after the main developer Kaldaien) is a mod that started as a mod for Batman: Arkham Knight and Fallout 4 of a few small games to tweak and fix their poor state of performance. It later became known as a mod for NieR: Automata in 2017 (which I know nothing about), and by 2020, spread out to a lot of games. A few Minecraft: Java Edition Java args guides recommend Special-K due to a feature called &amp;quot;OpenGL-IK&amp;quot;, which is a OpenGL to DirectX11 wrapper.&lt;br&gt;
Don&#39;t get it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Quick Explanation of a &amp;quot;wrapper&amp;quot;, the difference between OGL and DX11, etc&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That probably flew over your head, because it seems that a small portion of people who I show my blogs have no idea how anything works. No problem, let&#39;s simplify!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &amp;quot;wrapper&amp;quot; is a type of mod or tweak that wraps (haha, get it) around a program to change how a part of it works or starts. Steam is, technically, a wrapper for games that lets you use Steam to invite friends and invite people to your game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &amp;quot;graphics api wrapper&amp;quot;, which is what OpenGL-IK is, is pretty much the same thing. OpenGL-IK is like a translation. You can&#39;t speak French, right? You need a translator to hear the french (their first language) to tell it to you in English (their second language). Graphics wrappers work that way, it takes all of the OpenGL features and turns it into DirectX11 features, which sometimes lets programs that require DirectX11 (such as shaders) to work properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that sounds amazing! How does that relate to minecraft?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;If only it worked&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, exactly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special K and Minecraft have... Well, literally zero documentation. Here&#39;s a display of what appears on the google search for &amp;quot;SpecialK Minecraft&amp;quot;:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://images2.imgbox.com/a8/fa/eEJN5mkM_o.png&quot; alt=&quot;Only the first and second result were relevant.&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://images2.imgbox.com/4c/38/yTbFpqp5_o.png&quot; alt=&quot;Only the first result was relevant.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow. That&#39;s not cool at all! The only documentation that exists is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Mukul1127/Minecraft-Java-Flags&quot;&gt;some guide that doesn&#39;t even answer any questions!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Well... Yeah. Because it&#39;s probably not even tested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minecraft is a hard game to run, especially if you don&#39;t play Bedrock. Java runs on... Well, Java. and Java is meant to run for many programs, not just Minecraft! So, when it comes to injecting Special K, it might just inject into something it shouldn&#39;t. And well, chaos ensue. Makes sense that nobody tests Java edition!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you could try to run anyway, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;It was always busted&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you fucking serious?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s go back in time. That guide I linked before wasn&#39;t the first time Special K was proposed for Java! I had tried it in 2022 and didn&#39;t work, why else would I be bringing that up? I tried in 2024, it didn&#39;t work, and I think I had some kind of episode, because apparently the day after Feburary 2nd, where something &lt;em&gt;allegedly&lt;/em&gt; happened when I tried to talk it out with one of my family siblings that had been there for the incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, using SpecialK on a Java executable was probably a terrible idea, considering there was bound to be many issues. It&#39;s a dependancy, not the game engine, so... Volia, magic issues from nowhere.&lt;br&gt;
There is also the consideration that Special K is, well... A fucking NieR mod. It was probably not going to play fair anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;There is more complications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it probably also wasn&#39;t just that. I run Rivertuna Statistic Servers, an addon for MSI Afterburner that shows off the funny CPU Usage and temperature overlays you see in a lot of benchmark videos. I specifically only installed this on Ultrakill and Minecraft, because ROBLOX has an anti-cheat and anything else is probably not getting played any time soon. That&#39;s quite fine for me, I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But RTSS is infamously buggy with Minecraft. It &amp;quot;works&amp;quot;, sure, but if you use an old version of Minecraft where you need Sodium, it gets pretty ugly. Lots of things can go wrong, and since RTSS hooks into game, it doesn&#39;t &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; fuck with Anti-Cheats. And Minecraft happened to be one of these things, unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s also consider that I&#39;m a modder, which means, well... modding. I&#39;ve used Windhawk in the past (when my main rig used Revert8Plus), I&#39;ve used ExplorerPatcher in the past (windows 10 taskbar for windows 11 &amp;amp; windows 10 taskbar tweaks in general), my system is tweaked out with so many (debatably to some professionals) unrecommended and unnecessary tweaks that probably are doing more harm than good, etc. There&#39;s many possible faults, and you can&#39;t really throw a dart and find the one spot where we failed. It could be almost anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;My last install&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, getting back on track, I tried to install it yesterday. Let&#39;s go through what happened, step by step:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day one (Install):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed Special-K&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed Special-K kernel driver for CPU Thermals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up with Minecraft, tweak some settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minecraft no longer appears on the taskbar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minecraft now sometimes doesn&#39;t close until force killed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweak with settings A LOT following these issues:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Window issues (When maximized game is fine, but once window res is changed, the window has black borders and all clicks are offset weirdly, it&#39;s hard to explain)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Randomly fixed window issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OSD does not display CPU temperature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SpecialK runs several times over itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day two (Uninstall):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Window issues again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Menu no longer opened&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Playing in-game is pleasant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fucked up CPU usage that isn&#39;t right? (maxxed out, very bad on fans)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google results not helpful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Yeah...&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special K on Minecraft is horrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s just so poorly tested and documented, I don&#39;t even know what could have went wrong. I could tweak settings hopefully and hope clicking SOMETHING helps, but considering Special K has so many issues with Minecraft, it&#39;s not worth it. We&#39;ll use just use Minecraft&#39;s in-game framerate limiter for now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe one day, some better parity. But for now, the guide lied to me, we&#39;ll keep rocking RTSS and Sodium&#39;s OpenGL-based engine. VulkanMod is getting some progress on Vulkan performance, but it&#39;s still got a long way to perfection, and it&#39;s incompatible with Sodium, so... We&#39;ll wait for now, I think!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The frustration of Minecraft server hunting, an interactive experience</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/minecraft-server-buddies-rant-v2/" />
    <updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/minecraft-server-buddies-rant-v2/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You ever had to sift through a bunch of Minecraft server ads on Reddit to find a good server you can settle in? Ever struggled &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; bad with trying to sift through a bunch of posts for servers you can&#39;t connect with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can&#39;t imagine that? Congratulations, you&#39;re a normal person and probably want to know how insane I am. Let&#39;s get started on that right about...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Now: A Server Crisis&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Need to control those damn headers better...&lt;br&gt;
Yes, titlecard. A server crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the traditional sense of &quot;everything&#39;s on fire and nothing&#39;s going to get better&quot;, looking for Minecraft Servers is easy. Making friends, debatable... But finding a server is actually quite easy, you pop open your favorite Minecraft server subreddit...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&#39;s that? There&#39;s a bunch of junk websites that host servers that give benefits such as teleporting to high paying players? GOD DAMNIT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Clarifying...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is specifically talking about &lt;i&gt;survival servers&lt;/i&gt;, by the way. Like plain SMP that your old streaming friends and you play to get together and goof off in survival, nothing fancy kind of Survival. Not the corpo server kind where they have ranks after ranks, lootboxes with crate keys, McMMO &lt;small&gt;which i have a grudge on, by the way&lt;/small&gt;, buyable unbans...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are talking strictly survival here. As it should be. Well, let&#39;s go look how the modern experience looks like &lt;i&gt;without&lt;/i&gt; those kind of servers. Yuck...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Old r/MinecraftBuddies&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first, we need to talk a bit more about what changed. Because the experience between 2022-2023 and ~2024 ongoing are completely different experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;h2&gt;r/MinecraftBuddies and r/MinecraftWhitelisted&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Somewhere around September 16th 2024, &lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/MinecraftBuddies/comments/1fifa3c/important_announcement_for_rminecraftbuddies/&quot; title=&quot;This will sound very extreme, but I think this is the 9/11 of r/MinecraftBuddies. But only because they still haven&#39;t added the &#39;NeedsBuddy&#39; flair back to r/MinecraftWhitelisted, god damint.&quot;&gt;r/MinecraftBuddies split up into r/MinecraftBuddies and r/MinecraftWhitelisted&lt;/a&gt;. While for any other person, this change seemed super insignificant, and possibly even very understandable -- this change marked something. The end of r/MinecraftBuddies being used for servers.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;When I used r/MinecraftBuddies around 2022 and 2023, it was mostly used for finding servers. It had the main purpose of finding small friend groups, sure, but it was mostly a server hunting tool. Whitelisted servers were posting all the time there and it was mostly just drowning out people who just wanted a few friends. Unfortunately, that&#39;s the era I loved the most. But for a silly reason.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You see, when they had flairs, you had a flair for finding a buddy, when it was split up between &quot;hosting for buddies&quot; and &quot;searching for buddies&quot;. So you could post saying you&#39;re looking for a buddy. But now that you can&#39;t do that, you can&#39;t really lazily post that you need a server and hope the good people come right to you. You have to actually post about wanting friends. And that kinda sucks.&lt;br&gt;
      So we&#39;re going to use r/MinecraftWhitelisted for this rant. Since that&#39;s most accurate to the r/MinecraftBuddies 2022 experience. At least, partially...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The r/MinecraftBuddies 2022 Experience&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;(retold with r/MinecraftWhitelisted)&lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;h3&gt;(please do not harass servers you see here, they have their lives and reasons)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s how this little hunt works. You open the subreddit, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2025/minecraft-server-buddies-rant-v2/reddit.com/r/MinecraftWhitelisted/new/&quot; title=&quot;Do this yourself only if you&#39;re willing to scroll a long while. You tend to see the same few servers. You have better luck going through r/mcservers or joining r/MinecraftBuddies&#39; Discord server right now.&quot;&gt;sort by new&lt;/a&gt; and bask in random, varying degrees of helpful offers. I would use screenshots for these posts, but I&#39;m too lazy to take a bunch of images. So let&#39;s do this way: I&#39;ll link the posts I find so you can look at the servers, and we&#39;ll go through together all the perks.&lt;br&gt;
      When you look at these posts for real, please be respectful! Sign up for any servers you like, but don&#39;t send them any hate. I am mostly just playing around here.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;With that being said... Let&#39;s go look. We&#39;ll only sample just one, just for a reference on how we look into a post.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;h2&gt;A sample size: &lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/MinecraftWhitelisted/comments/1lamw3z/ordinary_smp_vanilla_java_1215_fabric/&quot; title=&quot;This link goes to old reddit!&quot;&gt;Ordinary SMP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You will probably read the words &quot;Hermitcraft-like&quot; often. I don&#39;t know much about what it means in terms of expectations (and nobody&#39;s ever given me a proper explanation), but as far as I know, Hermitcraft-like servers:&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Focus on tight-knit communities (with varying degrees of success)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Usually have plugins at all times, ranging from small to big depending on the server&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Nearly always have a Shopping District (Diamond run servers is what you want here. Money/plugin based systems are also used by pay to win servers, so avoid them if you can)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Usually have their own &quot;seasons&quot; (they reset the server every once and a while for something fresh)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;With these conditions in mind, we should take a look at what we&#39;re bargining for! Let&#39;s start with our fellow SMP here.&lt;br&gt;
        It appears we get Bluemap (okay, okay...), a voice chat plugin (these vary! I always avoid servers that make it mandatory because you&#39;ll hate them as an introvert anyway, but usually servers that force it either are likely dead or are content creation focused. some are fine though, and leave this as an option!), PvP and other world events (the PvP part has me worried), and, well... A server.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;These kind of servers usually make you yap about yourself, by the way. It&#39;s pretty comparable to a job interview, but the only difference is that there&#39;s less pressure here. They don&#39;t expect you to say a whole lot of nothingburger and lie about your experience... Just that you write a few sentences every question so they can tell you&#39;re serious.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;But this also puts strain on somebody like me, who doesn&#39;t quite always have the energy to sugarcoat an application for a whitelisted server. Dumb questions like &quot;Tell us more about yourself&quot; and &quot;How long have you been playing Minecraft?&quot; begin to feel &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; feel like they&#39;re just trying to find a way to gate you unless you tell them everything about you. I struggle to find the logic in it, and on a really bad day, it turns me away near immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;More examples&lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll rapid fire three more examples fast. These will mostly just point out things I notice. &lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/MinecraftWhitelisted/comments/1laljt7/the_bob_smp/&quot; title=&quot;Really, could have loved to know how your application system works or something.&quot;&gt;this ad&lt;/a&gt; doesn&#39;t list much helpful information other than &quot;We have land claims and care about lore, join us!&quot;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/MinecraftWhitelisted/comments/1l9ijwf/welcome_to_the_krustykraft_smp/&quot; title=&quot;I see you so much... Am I dreaming?&quot;&gt;this ad&lt;/a&gt; is for Bedrock (great for some! but i prefer Java), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/MinecraftWhitelisted/comments/1laike1/sunset_retreat_smp_vanilla_18_1215_new_season/&quot; title=&quot;Hi, I attend here! Please don&#39;t butcher me!&quot;&gt;this ad&lt;/a&gt; is for an 18+ server.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;Kids game... not suitable for children?&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Yes, you read that correctly. An &lt;b&gt;18+&lt;/b&gt; server.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;These things go around like flies. The intention is that the older a person is, the more mature they are. A good chunk of servers limit their player counts to people over 16, which in fact, I couldn&#39;t meet the age range for a while! And then the 18+ servers began overflooding the 16+ and 17+ servers, which meant I had to wait until 2024 to get 18...&lt;br&gt;
        And now the standard 13+ servers are all extinct, it seems. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I say 13+ because that&#39;s the age limit in 90% of countries to use Discord, by the way. Discord is a popular medium for these whitelisted servers, you do an application through Discord and if you&#39;ve written enough for your job interview, they let you in and tell you how to get on.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;But the thing is, there&#39;s a lot of servers that aim for people over 18. Hell, I&#39;ve even seen servers for adults only for people over 20, 30... On a kids game. If this was ROBLOX, I would have crashed out, but since Minecraft is about a hundred times better (minus Hypixel and those other kinds of Minigame servers) with handling private interactions than ROBLOX will ever be. I mean, you can make a private survival world every time, for christs sake. Good luck getting that on ROBLOX on 50% of your favorite games...&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;But really, it&#39;s for maturity. The problem is that every teenager under that age range (13-15, or 13-17 depending on who you ask) can&#39;t join any servers with people in their age range. So that leaves the problem of having to skip 90% of the list. A problem I&#39;ve suffered through in 2022 when I was still a Teenager. And now I&#39;m an adult, so I see what I missed. But now my sibling is fresh 13, so... Shit.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Yeah, basically it&#39;s a pain in the ass.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Haunt - More Tired Than Scared</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2024/the-haunt-rant/" />
    <updated>2024-10-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2024/the-haunt-rant/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, it appears we have reached the point where ROBLOX has completely lost it&#39;s ways. The events ROBLOX is choosing to push out now all follow the same pattern, have almost no originality, and are complete dogshit.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Really, this is the fourth event in a ROW to start with the word &quot;The&quot;, be made in the &quot;Stock Owners First&quot; era, and the fourth in a row to earn a blog post from yours truly complaining about it. if you can accomplish this over four times in a row, you&#39;re clearly just sticking with making dogshit for the shock value. There is no other explanation why this event should suck any more than it is.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;But no, here we are. Roblox is making dookie events again, and I guess it&#39;s because they&#39;re bored? I don&#39;t fucking know. They do this every major season and it seems to just get worse and worse than the last. The event is now centered around halloween, following the last event being about empires. Keep in mind that the first entry in this event started as a &quot;&quot;easter&quot;&quot; event. Yes, the double quotes TWICE is necessary, because there was hardly any easter theming in the event. Then we got The Classic, while charming and had some history right, mostly appealed to the morons who wanted to be &quot;&quot;nostalgic&quot;&quot;. Then we got The Games, an absolutely hilariously named event with even more hilariously attempted tasks, which just once again served to ruin the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;And well, here we are. Fourth fucking time in a row we have to do this stupid shit. Do they not get bored of this already? Is there not already enough people screaming from below begging ROBLOX to stop releasing shitty events? Well, I guess they can&#39;t hear us, because they dropped another turd from above. I guess we have to get our hands dirty again.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;h1&gt;Problems, Problems and Money Making&lt;/h1&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This event was doomed to be dogshit from the start. About twenty minutes away from the event starting, servers restarted. I&#39;m going to be completely real, there were people guessing there was nothing behind the door in the first place and I think they&#39;re right. We were waiting there for minutes on end just hoping in vein something interesting happens. What else do you do with the fucking mental asylum looking manor design? It reminds me of another particular game I know of. But maybe it&#39;s best I keep my mouth shut.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This event is just dogshit. They restarted once for shits and giggles, twice to award people the join badge. They must have been really bored waiting for problems to fix and finally had to get off their ass last minute to add something behind the event front doors. What, were they afraid that exploiters would check behind the map before they did anything? Then fix the fucking exploits! Maybe then there wouldn&#39;t be anything to worry about!&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;That isn&#39;t even the worst part. I guess they also wanted us players to suffer on their behalf, because the event is only a week long, give and take some hours. I guess they really didn&#39;t learn from The Classic? The Hunt was a month long. The Classic was only 5 days, but The Games was about three weeks. Now they&#39;re back to one week, because I guess they like forcing time crunches on people. Fucking hell.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It&#39;s clear they don&#39;t give a shit about you too, because when you get to the center room where all the important things take place, there&#39;s a headless horseman playing piano. Guess what that is! It&#39;s called a fucking upsell. They&#39;re trying to sell you a 31k bundle this year, let alone the fact it&#39;s like four hundred dollars. Go suck off your parents kids, or you can&#39;t be cool like us! Like all the bundle does is remove your head, why would you want that shit so desperately? That doesn&#39;t need to be in the lobby, get out of here!&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;h1&gt;Conflicting Interests&lt;/h1&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You want to know what I think about the game selection this year? It&#39;s as bad as The Games.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It was really bad during The Games. There were many conflictions, such as Dress To Impress and Fashion Famous, Funky Friday and RoBeats. Not to mention by that point, Adopt Me had made it into three events in a row. Interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Well, I guess The Haunt took that and cranked it up to about eleven. Because not only has Adopt Me, the least scariest game imaginable has made it to a fourth event, but there&#39;s even MORE conflictions! Get this: Pressure and Doors. That&#39;s a combo you weren&#39;t expecting, huh? Not to mention we again have Dress to Impress.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It doesn&#39;t even end there, they got ROYALE HIGH to participate. I don&#39;t know if you&#39;re aware, but Royale High is supposed to be about getting grades up, trading tails and looking sharp, not about dodging the known horrors of society. It&#39;s actually fucking impressive what kind of ways they fucked up this year.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Okay, sure, theoretically you could make a monster in Royale High, but it&#39;s not as effective as a REAL horror game, which is something that is of note. you know what else isn&#39;t a &quot;real horror game&quot;? SLAP BATTLES. The choices the developers have made when picking out games this year is borderline impressive and it still gives me shock how little they tried.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;h1&gt;Straying from Familiarity&lt;/h1&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You know how events are supposed to go, right? You join games participating, do tasks, get items. That&#39;s how it&#39;s been for the past three events, and how it&#39;s been... since forever.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Okay, now guess how you get items in The Haunt.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;That&#39;s right, taking screenshots, sending them to let others vote, and letting people vote on them to see what gets the most upvotes! You fucking dumbasses didn&#39;t think it was something else, right?!&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Yes, that is what they&#39;re doing now. Now you have to explore the game lobby to find things, and how do you explore the lobby? Wait for shit to open up! Fucking genius, right? And this opens random bums up to send inappropiate screenshots, or even downright awful screenshots. In fact, it&#39;s ENCOURAGED because you can get certain items, BY UPLOADING SCREENSHOTS. That is the event. I have explained the entire event, in about a few sentences. Event&#39;s over, you can go home now.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It&#39;s actually impressive. Half of the time you can get a vote but they&#39;re all garbage, one being a random ass screenshot of a dude flexing his pets, one of a guy running from a nextbot, one of somebody&#39;s ROYALE HIGH OUTFIT, and another that you can&#39;t even comprehensibly explain by adding more than &quot;it&#39;s offtopic&quot;. Holy shit.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;And in the end, you get your items, right? Guess what day one&#39;s item is.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;P&gt;an RHTRO item. This is a fucking joke.&lt;/P&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;And you want to know the crazy part? Not even VOTING worked on day one. The VOTING. Think about that.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;Hr&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Pop quiz, what&#39;s the one thing that should be kept in mind when making an interface?&lt;br&gt;If you said anything that isn&#39;t &quot;usability&quot;, you&#39;re just as bad as a ROBLOX event developer.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;And that isn&#39;t no fucking hyperbole, The Haunt has the worst UI design I&#39;ve seen so far. But who the fuck cares about that, right?&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Clearly they still don&#39;t care now, because four events later, there is STILL a gold track. So on top of all the technical issues, on top of the confusing changes, on top of having to WAIT for areas to open up, on top of the bad UI designs and the confusing game choices and every other flaw that has plagued this event series since FEBURARY, we have still not thought that we have made enough money to quit the GOLD TRACK.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;And I have to end the blog there. Because there&#39;s literally ZERO game objectives to talk about. I cannot expand the blog any more because they decided voting on screenshots was a better user experience than the shit from the past few events. THIS was their solution to fixing the bad game choice? Instead of actually getting competent developers to run the event instead of cash grabs, they just stop them from doing ANYTHING fun. This is like when the preschooler teacher takes everybody&#39;s recess time because one guy misbehaves. And in turn, you can&#39;t have a funny blog shitting on the flaws of this event.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It is fucking IMPRESSIVE how lazy they are. Anything but a proper fucking event, right! ANYTHING BUT SOMETHING FUCKING LIKABLE. They like to reuse the same animations, the same frames, the same fucking ideas and the only thing they change up is the ONE thing that should not have been changed.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;They don&#39;t even give you a reason to play. I&#39;m sure as hell not playing this.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Incompetence in Compensation, A Windows Rant</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2024/windows-rant/" />
    <updated>2024-10-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2024/windows-rant/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Do It To Death&lt;/h1&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Why, yes, I can hear it now! I can hear the screaming in the distance, the voices asking me to stop! I can hear them scream to me again, asking.&lt;br&gt;
    No, BEGGING me to stop squashing their golden system! And my response, my friend... I must say that I &lt;small&gt;do not give a single fuck what you think and think your bibilical angel needs to be burned!&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Why are you booing me? I&#39;m right!&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;A Sinful Miracle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a completely broken down fucking piece of shit. &lt;a href=&quot;https://djs4gnx.github.io/blog/posts/2023-03-08-Technology-is-Like-Magic.html&quot; title=&quot;A great post, but it has to be crapped on for today.&quot;&gt;This is going to be no nice post about the sunflowers,&lt;/a&gt; because oh boy, I am so fucking over that. There can only be so much sprinkes on a shit cake, and I&#39;ve been done trying to say positive things about this OS for a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way we have become glued to this piece of shit is just horrible. We&#39;re being forced to work with this dogshit because the entire computer market is nothing but putting the consumer on a leash. &quot;Don&#39;t let that motherfucker move more than an inch, it might break a battery!&quot;. Fucking pathetic. You can wave your warrenty just by fucking breathing. Disable Secure Boot? No warrenty for you, little boy! Doesn&#39;t matter if it was a mistake you made fumbling the bios or on purpose to change your boot screen logo, it&#39;s gone FOREVER! Thanks a lot, UEFI. God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I haven&#39;t even gotten to the fun part yet. Grand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Fun (Not Responding)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh how convenient, the header is not responding. A perfect opening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That intro was pretty scattered. Not enough content, and too much randomness. Let&#39;s fix that by introducing the most infuriating thing that has been invented for ANY operating system ever: that grey overlay piece of shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put your computer under enough load, and that piece of shit will appear. A simple game loading screen? Good chance you saw that when you clicked too much! Sitting in a system chug because it doesn&#39;t do your bidding and it&#39;s taking five hours to extract a zip file? You bet it&#39;s gonna stop responding! Try to speak and write this blog, not responding. Write a tweet, not responding. Can&#39;t even wipe my own- Oh, we&#39;re not that far enough into the blog to use that kind of language.&lt;br&gt;
Well fuck the kids, they can just look away, can&#39;t they?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows just has a full PASSION for locking everything up, it&#39;s not even always through that piece of shit grey overlay. Sometimes it likes to prevent the mouse from going under the taskbar. Sometimes it likes to completely freeze the machine, locking up the mouse and sometimes the screen while leaving whatever you were hearing through the speakers going. Happened to be playing that annoying song you wanted to skip? Well, try to have fun when the computer locks up and all you can hear now is that annoying fucking music, locking you in purgatory for trying to have free thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shit is like a mutation, it&#39;s like everybody&#39;s form of it is different. Sometimes, explorer will restart. Sometimes it will not. Sometimes your programs will all quit at once when the computer unfreezes. Sometimes, it will return. It&#39;s fucking random, you get what I&#39;m saying?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AND DON&#39;T EVEN GET ME STARTED ON-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Glued to the Tape&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, here it is. The thing I&#39;ve been talking about nonstop for the past few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows is a complete clusterfuck that makes you clutch on bandaids. Send that to r/brandnewsentence, but it&#39;s a true thing that&#39;s been tried and shown, ESPECIALLY if you know what it&#39;s like to use a shell that isn&#39;t Explorer.&lt;br&gt;
  To put it short, it&#39;s a customization shitshow, and it gets worse the more you update. And once you go back, it&#39;s basically too late. You wanna see what that looks like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine you&#39;re on the latest version, like I imagine you are. In the last update, about four of your favorite gimmicks got nuked. Your color is now windows black instead of that nice grey or whatever neon color you use. Half of your icons got reset back and you have to wait two months for an update before you can change the icons back. In the meantime, more updates will undoubtably be released to make this take longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, about two very random things have been broken. What two random things, you say? Guess! Imagine two completely obscure and random features you use on Windows, if you can. Maybe one day you find out you can&#39;t open a specific menu you only use to change your default browser. Or maybe you&#39;re trying to print something and the menu is just completely fucked. THAT is how it feels to customize windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, well that&#39;s about updates breaking things. But surely, you don&#39;t use anything special, surely you don&#39;t need all of this junk? &lt;small&gt;loud incorrect buzzer&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is what the situation ACTUALLY looks like. You use Windows Search, right? You&#39;re trying to find a file? Maybe you&#39;re looking for that PDF you need for work. Or maybe you&#39;re holding onto a text file with your passwords. Maybe you just need help finding the program you use every day? Yeah, that thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it&#39;s junk. It&#39;s slow garbage, that&#39;s what it is. At least, in 10 and over. It might work fine, but the slower your hardware is, the more the seconds feels like minutes. You don&#39;t want to take five minutes to search a file, right? You don&#39;t want to be fucked in that way, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what you do. You slap &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.voidtools.com/&quot; title=&quot;Genuinely the best file searching program you&#39;ll ever need. Enter a file name, maybe some nerd stuff default Windows doesn&#39;t have, and you&#39;re golden brown. Just mind the long caching times, it&#39;s normal.&quot;&gt;Voidtools Everything&lt;/a&gt; on it. Cool, good as new. Except it&#39;s not, because that&#39;s only a file search. You need to find your programs and settings too, right? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flowlauncher.com/&quot; title=&quot;Genuinely cool piece of software! Too bad I have crashing issues that seem randomly triggered.&quot;&gt;Flow launcher&lt;/a&gt;, discussion finally over, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, it is not. We are not even STARTED. Not only are you still likely to have crashes on crappy hardware (especially hard drives), this is just a bandaid fix. And surprise, you&#39;re not even CLOSE to done talking about all the things you have to replace!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;File Explorer is also crap. Unresponsible, buggy, completely confusing junk with no advanced ideas. Not to mention Microsoft wants ads &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2024/4/24/24138949/microsoft-windows-11-start-menu-ads-recommendations-setting-disable&quot; title=&quot;The fuck were they thinking? Get this off my screen, I want to open Firefox!&quot;&gt;where you launch your apps&lt;/a&gt;, in your face, in the background, and even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/microsoft/microsoft-is-testing-ads-in-the-windows-11-file-explorer/&quot;&gt;While you&#39;re searching for your PDFs&lt;/a&gt;! What the fuck? Get this off my screen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, well that&#39;s pretty lame. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gpsoft.com.au/&quot; title=&quot;The price is pretty high, and I don&#39;t agree with it&#39;s charging for future updates, but it&#39;s genuinely good if you can afford it.&quot;&gt;Let&#39;s get Directory Opus&lt;/a&gt; and that will surely be done now- oh, right, you don&#39;t like subscriptions. Well, that one looked cool, but that&#39;s okay, we&#39;ll get &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xyplorer.com/&quot; title=&quot;Their free version is very old and I couldn&#39;t find it, FYI. Way cheaper than DOpus, though!&quot;&gt;XYPlorer&lt;/a&gt; instead and-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you mean, you have no cash? God, okay, we&#39;ll settle for &lt;a href=&quot;https://explorerplusplus.com/&quot;&gt;Explorer++&lt;/a&gt; instead, good god. You can put up with the instability that it magically has. Remember to pick up the dev build, the release build is 1.4 which was last updated in Janurary, pretty old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;May 2025 Dj here: The above was from 2024. One year ago. And the latest stable is still v1.4. They are so behind, man.&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or you can try, because it&#39;s just as bad as File Explorer. Bookmarks are definitely an improvement and so are tabs (especially for my fellow outdated peeps), but holy SHIT do they design these like crap. I must have had over six crashes and maybe broke the shell integration at least twice? It&#39;s fucking amazing how this is still up, considering how busted it is. I used this back in march and it was SO bad, I persued Directory Opus through the means I knew. Do you know how bad you have to program a core system function to make a user PERSUE a drop-in replacement for the shell? That problem should have been left with Windows 95 and WINSTEP. Not with 10+.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Update Gambit&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was about to summon you. Let&#39;s talk about gambling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You like randomly throwing money with a near guarenteed chance to with nothing? Good, I assume you also do it on the daily, day in and day out every night when your wife isn&#39;t looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cool, and you ever wanted to do that with a software update? Update day in and day out with a chance to lose your operating system and experience a really fucking dumb bug? Damn, that&#39;s too bad, you can do it anyway lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a bad update for everybody, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pcworld.com/article/2407587/july-windows-10-update-causes-blue-screen-reboot-loops-heres-the-fix.html&quot; title=&quot;This is a real side effect from the result of a Microsoft update. Great gut, M$.&quot;&gt;causing frequent laptop BSoDs after install&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laptopmag.com/laptops/windows-laptops/gamers-on-windows-11-are-fuming-over-performance-issues-but-theres-a-fix&quot;&gt;a magic update nuking your gaming performance&lt;/a&gt;, there is a new way to be fucked by everybody, for everybody. Considering how basically every year there&#39;s guarenteed to be at least one bad update pushed out, it&#39;s a miracle there hasn&#39;t been street riots over this shit. Can you imagine going to work and one day when you install new floors, the floor now is always bent? You would have not bought them old floors again, right? Why let Microsoft do that to you themselves? What&#39;s different?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updates on their own are a beast and a half, just complete rigged garbage. How this company hasn&#39;t been completely cooked is beyond me considering every second update has a virutal bomb strapped to it. Every update is different for everybody, where one person can install it normally, when I try to install 22H2 Windows 11 suddenly the properties menu is all fucked and I no longer have a taskbar. What the fuck? What happened to &quot;If it works, don&#39;t fix it&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you have to go through a bunch of work to undo the updates. This is even worse if your display is cooked or you&#39;re a complete dumbass who doesn&#39;t know how to use a desktop for shit. It&#39;s also twice as bad from my end because I&#39;m a laptop and my internal display is cooked. So I&#39;m basically stuck and have to preserve my install as long as possible since I can&#39;t navigate the BIOS or anything. Great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Windows on Ol&#39; Dinosaur&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want another place to throw shade? Throw it at the manefacturers. They&#39;re sticking Dinosaurs in new computers. Open that baby up and you&#39;ll probably find a hard drive in there. NOT an SSD. It&#39;s just dogshit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So not only is the system coded like garbage, the manefacturers are undermining your intelligence. Well no shit, when you put in a 5200RPM drive, it&#39;ll run like shit. But nobody wants to put in the work of fixing their shit, they just want their stuff to look mighty and grand, for fucks sake. Who cares about performance when we can automatically assume everybody has a NASA computer? Let&#39;s focus on animations and other ridiculous overmined junk. Sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now watch, as I make my disappearance! And come back later with a sequel.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Browsers, extensions, other floorp &amp; my browsing history</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2024/my-browser-history/" />
    <updated>2024-09-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2024/my-browser-history/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;...Oh. It&#39;s already time to talk about Floorp. Well, I guess it&#39;s time for The Switch from Spotify 2. This will just be a buckshot full of bullshit, isn&#39;t it?&lt;br&gt;
Welp, might as well get our hands dirty with lead while we can. Let&#39;s talk about browsers. kameron the gun talk doesn&#39;t add any spice to the blog please stop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;A Naive Start&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, sure, I was very corny right there to talk a little tough. We&#39;re talking about something as simple as browsers, what kind of r/brandnewsentence post is &amp;quot;Buckshot full of bullshit&amp;quot;, right?&lt;br&gt;
But that&#39;s the thing. The land of internet browsers is just a bit of a heavy war with a bunch of teens, hipsters and nerds in trenchcoats fighting over which browser is the best subjectively. There&#39;s a bunch of gossip here and there, especially on r/Browsers, there&#39;s &amp;quot;opera is spyware&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;chrome is great&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;firefox eats more ram&amp;quot;, but there&#39;s always that one guy willing to either ride the toxic train to defend his favorite browser, bad or not. But that&#39;s not what this kind of blog is. Let&#39;s talk as though we&#39;re just a regular user, looking for a browser to use.&lt;br&gt;
Because that&#39;s just who I was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Surfin&#39; like Joe: Early Choices&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you can get to power, you have to be on the bottom rung. And that&#39;s where the backstory comes in. kameron it doesn&#39;t sound badass in your head you know that by trying to repeat this same joke you- shut up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was saying, we have to talk about the powerless days before we can get right to power user era. Let&#39;s talk about my history of browsers, and oh boy there&#39;s a lot of them! Firefox will be last since that&#39;s the main focus, and we have to get through the garbage first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Internet Explorer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m covering this one fast because the humor value really seemed like it would align in my favor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet Explorer... The infamous &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/windows98/comments/gssowg/active_desktop_in_windows_98/&quot; title=&quot;Active Desktop is a common criticism by people who say this.&quot;&gt;bloatware browser&lt;/a&gt; known for &lt;a href=&quot;http://toastytech.com/evil/ieisevilstory.html&quot; title=&quot;Nobody actually liked IE. Cue the shock.&quot;&gt;being bundled since 98&lt;/a&gt;, and overall &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.howtogeek.com/32372/htg-explains-why-do-so-many-geeks-hate-internet-explorer/&quot; title=&quot;I couldn&#39;t think of any other better way to explain this, so here&#39;s a How To Geek article.&quot;&gt;being hated&lt;/a&gt; by many. I only ever used this browser as a joke, except for the one specific website that only worked properly when opened in IE for some reason. Internet Explorer is a huge joke, as implied on the box.&lt;br&gt;
It&#39;s just slow, unnecessarily bundled with your computer, died pretty fast, and died when Firefox and Chrome came on the scene. For good reason too, this browser&#39;s UI is okay, but the rest is kind of crap. It&#39;s clearly aged since it was last supported, and other browsers have more than enough features. IE is pretty barebones in it&#39;s current state, and basically unsupported by 90% of modern webpages. Only good for downloading Chrome. 0/10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A powerhouse for some, sure. A RAM eater? A classic! A viable browser that is going to last long enough for my needs? What is this, Things To Do When Bored 2, no!&lt;br&gt;
Oh, you&#39;re waiting for me to say I&#39;m joking. Well, in that case, I&#39;m sorry for your loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh boy, Google Chrome, the browser with a really high market share. This was basically the browser my sibling and I used repeatedly on and off for the first few years. Chrome might as well be called the &amp;quot;fox killer&amp;quot; the way it basically killed Firefox when it came onto the scene. While simple and pretty, sure, it&#39;s just not ideal for my uses. Let&#39;s talk a little bit more about the history I used it, since this is a key factor with a lot of these browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Early Uses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprise, back in the day, I was like you! Didn&#39;t ask for ANYTHING in a browser. If it watched YouTube and opened ROBLOX, maybe The Useless Web, it was perfect enough. I wasn&#39;t aware of profile themes, wasn&#39;t aware of uBlock Origin, wasn&#39;t aware of anything else. If anything, I used Adblock Plus of all things... Gross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried a few extensions, sure, but nothing special. I was stupid and naive enough to fall for ABP&#39;s bullshit, not even asking questions when it failed to block ads. And I just chugged on, going through my life as normal. Not one second thought about the browser I was using, it was just what I used.&lt;br&gt;
Well it would hit me pretty hard when my eyes opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yeah, maybe, perhaps, I tried a few russian forks... By coincidence. But in the end, it was just a personal trip for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;End of the Road&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things changed drastically in the past few years. Google has become the controversy of many scandals. They&#39;re caught up in anti-privacy lawsuit bullshits, they pay many people including Mozilla (creator of Firefox, if you&#39;re not aware), Apple, and almost everybody else, just to be the top search engine. But everybody knows how widespread it is to say &amp;quot;Google has your data&amp;quot;. But as far as I know, not many people bother to switch away, so everybody just willingly pays Google in Data, I guess. The ways you could just wish to say ABCDE Fuck You to some people. (I&#39;m putting it the nice way, by the way)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that was not the only way I willingly opened my eyes. I finally started to give a shit about the kind of ads I was being shown and such, and finally turned to uBlock Origin. Then more recently, Google released Manifest V3 and basically completely neutered adblockers as a side effect.&lt;br&gt;
Oh, you thought that was bad? Read a bit more about the whole YouTube adblock scandal. All of a sudden, YouTube Premium is this big thing to Google and they started playing with the patience of it&#39;s users by blocking adblockers and bricking them all willy nilly. Forget cat and mouse, play Google&#39;s game of outcast and lawmaker. You can have your adblock stripped of effectiveness AND get to be hounded to turn off adblock for completely free! Your four stacked AdBlocks won&#39;t save you now, Timmy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post isn&#39;t just about spreading gospel about Google&#39;s shitty services that everybody&#39;s glued to though. Not only does the &amp;quot;getting bored&amp;quot; effect come into play just like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kam106.neocities.org/blog/posts/2024-08-26-The-Switch-From-Spotify&quot; title=&quot;Direct link to that blog post, where I talk more about this effect!&quot;&gt;The Switch from Spotify&lt;/a&gt;, but also comes the new futures you got used to in the time you were away! No proper APIs for tab management or customizing the UI means that now you can&#39;t twice bake your little Tree Style Tabs or Sideberry extension to the side. The closest you get is &lt;a href=&quot;https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/forest-tree-style-tab-man/hbledhepdppepjnbnohiepcpcnphimdj&quot; title=&quot;This is the extension I used to get this behavior on anything Chromium. This covers Chrome, Brave, Vivaldi, and every non-firefox thing you like in between. Explain switching to Brave now, try hards. (sarcastic)&quot;&gt;this shitty watered down version&lt;/a&gt; that doesn&#39;t stay on screen when you click a tab, along with also being covered up by your browser&#39;s topbar tab design. All for free!&lt;br&gt;
Get where this goes yet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you like a feature of another browser and it&#39;s not available, through extension or otherwise, then it&#39;s really hard to life hack it back into the browser because guess what, no alternative exists! And if no alternative exists, you can&#39;t enjoy your browser. Chrome is a GREAT way to explain the base state of &amp;quot;browsers&amp;quot; because people often just use Chrome raw with no real value or additions except maybe their four stacked adblockers that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Adblock/comments/3sz9w5/any_harm_in_running_multiple_adblock_plugins/&quot; title=&quot;If you have more than one adblocker installed right now, get rid of all of them and install uBlock Origin (or uBO Lite if not on firefox). Many people will tell you to NOT do this, including people who make adblockers! Pick a good adblocker and don&#39;t use anything else.&quot;&gt;commit war crimes to humanity&lt;/a&gt;. Also, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock/wiki/uBlock-vs.-ABP:-efficiency-compared&quot; title=&quot;If the pirates, nerds, and even I&#39;m telling you to switch, YOU NEED TO SWITCH! Forget what your friends said.&quot;&gt;maybe stop using Adblock Plus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuck chrome. Chromium is a step up but still bad. If you REALLY want this garbage for some reason, just use Thorium. This browser is just a case of ignorance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quote the thought process of the companies, as said by Kanye West:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;quot;I don&#39;t take advice from people less successful than me.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, we just started and we already dumped an essay into Google Chrome, a classic example of sheep society syndrome. Well, the next step is to actually get the rest of the browsers out of the way, so...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Maxthon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, maybe I do not have as much information as I thought I did, so sorry in advance for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://news.softpedia.com/images/extra/WINDOWS2/large/Maxthon3_04large.png&quot; alt=&quot;Maxthon 3 screenshot&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, I had an obsession with Maxthon 3.x, as shown to your right. I guess like some later choices here, I ran it alongside other browsers, which made a whole mess of my browsing choice, a classic move from back in the day. Coming from the same person who had a million folders on their desktop when they were like 10, what might be a better explanation for you: I WANTED TO BE UNIQUE!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.lo4d.com/t/screenshot/maxthon-cloud-browser-4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Maxthon 4 screenshot&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, would you look at that, it&#39;s Adshow Plus! Yeah, back in the day this browser had like, notetaking stuff, and for some reason the downloads panel was handled by an extension, but I don&#39;t remember there being an extension for games. That&#39;s quite interesting. Excuse the watermark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This browser is old and I can&#39;t verify if it&#39;s good or not, so maybe test in a VM first. This kind of browser was interesting, but of course, it didn&#39;t last. Sure, it cemented my blind and uneducated opinion that AdBlock Plus was above all else, but we&#39;re all trying our best in the end. And I did eventually make the switch!&lt;br&gt;
Right, we&#39;re offtopic again. Point is, Maxthon didn&#39;t last. I got focused on Opera, and of course, I wanted to hop ships as soon as I heard of another random browser. So that&#39;s what I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Opera&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, listen to me for just one minute. I did not add this browser JUST because of the spyware bullshit. That is not the main reason why this is here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I do have to throw it into the ring, so &lt;a href=&quot;https://rentry.co/operagx&quot;&gt;here&#39;s some things that they&#39;ve seemingly done&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/browsers/comments/1f664su/browser_recommendation_megathread_september_2024/&quot;&gt;here is r/browser&#39;s current recommendation thread&lt;/a&gt;, tell them what features you use and just get going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Early Uses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Done glazing? Had enough of the ol&#39; &amp;quot;They say they&#39;re from&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;But it works fine on&amp;quot; crap? Okay, you earned a couple of minutes of screentime, but nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www-static-blogs.operacdn.com/desktop/wp-content/uploads/sites/3/2015/01/tab-preview-opera-27-computers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Opera 27 screenshot&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to use Opera back when it still looked like this! It was before they were purchased in 2016 and it was a completely different beast then than it tends to be now. My reasons for using this browser when I was really young was mainly &amp;quot;haha I&#39;m unique for using this&amp;quot;, and sometimes I would run it alongside Opera for... well, shits and giggles. Which explains the warcrime. I also would try a bunch of random browsers that were forks of existing browsers, not knowing what forks were or what the difference was. I always appreciated Opera&#39;s design though, despite not knowing what had actually happened to the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not completely understand the extensions the browser used, sure, but it seemed neat at the time, as did early Firefox of the time. And it remained like that for a while. Until...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Abandoning Opera&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuck you, sudden switchup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I eventually suddenly dropped Opera, around 2016. Why? I don&#39;t remember, I was ten years old! But it was a good run as I moved on to other places, specifically Firefox, I think. This browser is kind of just mediocre, not really my kind of recommendation. ESPECIALLY not in modern day, the UI is confusing and overall the browser is just sketchy. But with that in mind, note Opera for a little longer, because the next section is not too far behind!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Surfin&#39; like Joe: Later Days&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Opera GX&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, if it isn&#39;t the queen of hot garbage in all of it&#39;s glory! I knew it would come up eventually Whew, we&#39;re going to have a very long talk with this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opera GX, if you haven&#39;t heard of it, is an RGB shitfest. It has a bunch of wild features all willy nilly, makes use of a lot of &amp;quot;gamer&amp;quot; gimmicks, and a bunch of unneeded sidebars I don&#39;t want on my screen. Though I have to admit, the idea to make a sound when you press a key is pretty satisfying... Well, it doesn&#39;t justify the weird shit this company does, but I gotta say that the sound is nice at least... Until you look at the alternatives, but that&#39;s for another day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opera seems to like injecting a bunch of weird gimmicks like this for no reason. I don&#39;t think if they think it makes them any less sketchy, or they think that injecting a bunch of weird stuff into their browser makes it easier to appeal to gamers, or what... It&#39;s weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to mention the whole UI is like some kind of gay rainbow poop, but here we are! Right in the middle of I don&#39;t know, 2020, trying some browsers I haven&#39;t heard of in several years. I would go on and off with this browser for a few years, occasionally going back to this browser like crack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;End of the Line&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It did NOT take long for this ship to crash down, and it took at fast as it did to build it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only had I discovered through my own use that the resource limiters were basically complete junk (only served to nerf the browser experience at that point, except maybe the RAM limiter which could be accomplished with tab suspending anyway), the VPN is actual dogshit. Not to mention, some really cool nerds &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Godiesc/firefox-gx&quot;&gt;basically implimented a recreation of the Opera GX UI for Firefox.&lt;/a&gt; Go figure, even that was taken from them by now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so most, if not, all gimmicks from Opera GX were implimented in Firefox by now, considering it&#39;s not hard to go look for them. After all, &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/gx-mods/&quot; title=&quot;It even handles installing GX Mods, just like the title says! And you can change the sounds this way.&quot;&gt;Background noises &amp;amp; keyboard noises&lt;/a&gt;, the UI (as talked about earlier), &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/clipboard2file/clipboard2file&quot; title=&quot;Doesn&#39;t include recently downloaded, but to be fair, who is grabbing files from their recently downloaded that much?&quot;&gt;grabbing images from clipboard&lt;/a&gt;, and some more, I think. So there&#39;s really no point in using Opera GX for me at this point. The UI is kind of okay, but it&#39;s not real rocket science either. Plus all the gimmicks are kind of just optional things I can live without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless if you&#39;re careless or genuinely somehow believe limiting your CPU usage on a browser will help you, this browser is pretty barebones and mediocre. Not my first choice, and somewhere around my last right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that was a bust too. Chrome has controversy behind it, Opera has controversy behind it, what&#39;s next-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Brave&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah fuck, I knew that was coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This browser and I always had beef. I do not like this browser&#39;s inclusion of Cryptocurrency wallet bullshit and whatever other scandals it&#39;s trying to pull. It seems to have a huge obsession with crypto, something I don&#39;t really like. But hey, glory to crypto bros, I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, if it isn&#39;t another browser with a bunch of bullshit behind it. Everybody&#39;s favorite kind of pointless browser! Let&#39;s also add rum, beer and a full internet posting of my address before the day is completely done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who am I kidding when all people want is serious reactions and a bunch of ass kissing for their favorite overcorporate companies? Fine, let&#39;s talk about Brave, the browser that &lt;a href=&quot;https://spyware.neocities.org/articles/brave&quot; title=&quot;Spyware Watchdog is known to be a little sensitive and is most definitely outdated by now, so take anything you read with a grain of salt. Though, I have blocked some of these connections listed and did a bit of research on my HOSTS file.&quot;&gt;seems to love it&#39;s slippery telemetry&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techworm.net/2020/06/brave-browser-cryptocurrency.html&quot; title=&quot;Long story short: They injected into links to make money off the sites you visit.&quot;&gt;injecting into site links&lt;/a&gt;, and a bunch of other things. As you can expect for any modern company, they have a new AI assistant and their own built in adblocker which may or may not be good. On top of these, they also focus a lot of crypto, which may be distasteful to casual users. Specifically, they have their own fork of Etherium or whatever the fuck it&#39;s called, and they sure LOVE pumping bullshit into their browser, akin to Opera GX&#39;s Gimmicks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try not to get too excited though, as much as that sounds like fun. Brave is really just another Chromium fork like everything else, so you&#39;re really just using Chrome under the hood again. Though, you&#39;re free to believe that you&#39;re using something fancy. It&#39;s really just Chrome with a facelift. I think even my entire body is in pain realizing how many Chromium browsers we have right now. Oh god.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, fine! I hear you complaining across the screen that I fucked over the Opera GX part, and I need to do a better job with Brave. You want a fancy, long thought out post about why I don&#39;t like Brave? Here you go:&lt;br&gt;
It&#39;s literally just Chrome. The browser is almost functionally and visually just Chrome with some extra features. The features are not overly gimmicky like Opera GX is, but it still slightly bothers me that the features are all things I can already add on my own with extensions. I mean come on, I already use and AdBlocker, I don&#39;t need another one right up my ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This browser is alright for main use, sure but the amount of gimmicks it tries to pull as well as the browser&#39;s borderline addiction with cryptocurrency as well as it&#39;s mostly cultish fanbase, I would not recommend this out of a hobby. I would recommend this only if the use case fits. Seriously, come on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Woah, we&#39;re really getting through all the options, we might run out at this rate. As expected...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vivaldi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering how Vivaldi was recommended to me by one of my parents, the fact it comes from the original CEO of Opera, as well as it&#39;s expansive options for customization, I really wanted to like browser. However there is a lot of really strange behaviors to this browser and obvious performance issues that seems to impact the optimality of this browser. that&#39;s the right word right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This browser may be chromium browser, but it ticks all the right boxes with good customization, a pretty good track record, and even a nice cult following of users who know this browser in and out. However, this is not a glazing post, so let&#39;s talk about why I moved away from it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The performance of Vivaldi is a huge detriment to this browser, and that&#39;s pretty obvious, at least in my own use cases. Startup is horridly slow, it&#39;s amazing this browser is still around. This browser is lucky it&#39;s maybe a second runner up, the top actual king of slow load times is Windows itself, for obvious reasons. I already have Discord taking a written essay and a half to start up, Windows already barely starts up after a few serious errors, I do not need my personal WEB BROWSER to also take forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we break down the main points, let&#39;s first talk about the update notifier. Holy fuck, I hate this thing. It takes up space on my taskbar, the overflow menu, whatever. I want this shit off my screen, but it doesn&#39;t go away! I have to deliberately KILL a seperate process to stop this damn popup from appearing. Now is it in settings? Probably. Do I have time to go check the fucking settings page to turn off an annoying popup? No! Time is much better spent just removing the exe from the folder instead. It&#39;s literally faster. That&#39;s just one caveat in too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, main points. The peformance of Vivaldi is so bad, holy shit. Startup times are genuinely so awful, it&#39;s amazing how this browser is still working. It&#39;s like somebody put duct tape over an original Opera build and called it updated. Sure, it&#39;s ready for modern standards, but the performance and the overall stability is so bad, it&#39;s like it&#39;s run by tape and miracles. Not to mention the stability issues this browser has. As said in the words of another redditor, the obscure issues this browser seems to have is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a good joke for you, this browser&#39;s ability to make issues out of thin air! Love your web pages loading at all? Nah, go fuck yourself! Now your web pages refuse to load in the middle of May for no reason. Like using your browser as soon as it starts up? Bam, wait over 10 minutes to get even one page to load. Like holy fuck, let me breathe? Let me use the browser when it starts and not do ALL of your tasks at startup?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and this applies to general browser stability too. The browser, unprompted, crashed while trying to install a ROBLOX extension. This was when I was basically done downloading almost everything, and it genuinely impresses me how such a browser can be so awfully configured. Well, I guess I&#39;m sorry for expecting a browser to optimally load a web page without me being able to make a god damn coffee while it loads. I expect that from GTA V, not a browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this arguing aside though, and my own seemingly unlucky use case (or maybe not, since some redditors seem to have my issue), Vivaldi is a really good Chromium based browsers. Use anything you want from the Chrome store, a mediocre (and again worse than uBO but better than nothing) adblocker, as well as some customization options. Plus there&#39;s a mobile app for both iOS and Android to sync your profiles, and even themes if you really so desired. Make everything piss green if you felt like it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, following the changes that will happen with Manifest V3, Vivaldi will likely not be ideal forever. And you really need the power of uBO. Hey, that&#39;s slightly related to this next choice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Edge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will say this exactly once, and it will not be repeated in basic for the people who are terminally obsessed with glazing Edge.&lt;br&gt;
I do not like Microsoft Edge, at all.&lt;br&gt;
Anybody who tries to object or otherwise convince me that Edge is any more efficient than my current browser choice (coming later on) will be shot once. People who object to these rules will be shot twice.&lt;br&gt;
Survivors will be shot three times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I think the glazers left. Let&#39;s talk about the weird trailblazer that has a couple thousand geeks obsessed for some reason. I didn&#39;t know a single fucking person who willingly used the UWP version of Edge, but I guess as soon as they released a native, cross platform version of it, people love it. And a random &amp;quot;setup&amp;quot; popup came up, so I think Microsoft is trying to shut me down, but who cares about that?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jokes aside, this browser is a pretty big handful. Let&#39;s talk about the browser that is literally made by the person who created your operating system. Let&#39;s talk about the software that literally fucking begs you to not change your default browser, and was made to nag you. Let&#39;s talk about how in Windows 11, they made changes so you have to sit through this browser&#39;s annoying ass dog whimpering as you change that selection to Firefox. Let&#39;s talk about all the other ridiculous choices Microsoft makes to their operating systems that people love to brush off, because company whiplash and company backlash doesn&#39;t mean shit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, in case you can&#39;t tell, I have a huge hate for Microsoft, &lt;a href=&quot;http://toastytech.com/evil/rants.html&quot; title=&quot;God, fucking love the rants that Toasty Tech posts. Also, warning for a meme about suicide among all things.&quot;&gt;and I don&#39;t seem to share that sentiment on my own&lt;/a&gt;. I have the right to as well, Windows is overbloated and infamously made fun of worldwide. Windows 10 laptops are bundled with HARD DRIVES for fucks sake too, something that will undoubtably put headaches and strands on the users who use them in the future. Not to mention, the crazy fucking stunts Microsoft loves pulling for some reason, like the whole fucking Copilot AI, Recall shit. Like that&#39;s asking for free spyware to watch over your shoulder while you enter your password. That sounds like a gold mine for hacks to leak your password from! Millions of gigabytes of my images released for the world to see?! Having microsoft see private search history? How do I sign up?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This unholy dogshit is just a reincarnation of Internet Explorer, which by the way, STILL has it&#39;s ashes scattered everywhere. Microsoft seems to want to hide IE behind Edge. But they clearly didn&#39;t learn from IE, because they&#39;re trying to do the same shit as IE &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ShadowWhisperer/Remove-MS-Edge&quot; title=&quot;Basically, install pending updates, then run the tool. Otherwise you&#39;re fucked.&quot;&gt;by making uninstalling this garbage brick windows updates.&lt;/a&gt; I feel so in control of my computer! I do not feel hard fucked by this at all, nooo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it not enough they&#39;re pushing Telemetry down my throat every living minute I use my computer? Is it not enough they have ads on the file explorer, or that they try to install OneDrive with every moment, or that they auto bundle Office 365 with my computer which I have to manually uninstall all the time? What about how it automatically re-installs McAfee when I already know it&#39;s complete utter dogshit and that I&#39;ll be using Malwarebytes instead? I&#39;ve moved on from the old, naive thought of &amp;quot;If it works, why switch?&amp;quot;, I have more important things to care about now, like the shit going on my life, and the things companies are doing to fuck me over. I don&#39;t have time to do all of this extra annoying shit with every new computer. Why not just let me uninstall edge to make it easier instead of bricking any chance to update my god damn duct tape computer? The fuck were you thinking making this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And get this, people seem to love over appraising this browser somehow. This clearly makes it more than Internet Explorer because people seem to absolutely love pretending this browser saved their life or whatever. Watch as about four cultists and a member of the Hope County Choir comes to my Guestbook to raid it over my &amp;quot;bad take&amp;quot;. It&#39;s called a hot take by the way, you also misspelt &amp;quot;idiot&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This browser is, like Internet Explorer, only good for downloading Chrome while you get your shit sorted. Yet, unlike Internet Explorer, it has a cult following who for some reason ignores the crazy, unused trash that UWP Edge was. It&#39;s not really &amp;quot;impossible&amp;quot; to use this browser, persay, since it&#39;s still kind of functional...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, you don&#39;t even deserve that, this browser was ALWAYS shit. The UWP version was pointless, looked ugly, and had no real traditional or explained extension support. It was just a gimmick for Microsoft to convince it&#39;s users that they can still make good web browsers, for some very bizzare reason. The new native version? It&#39;s as bad as the fucking File Explorer. Do you know how long it takes for a File Explorer window to become usable? Take a guess.&lt;br&gt;
Over a minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directory Opus takes maybe 5 seconds at most. That&#39;s why I&#39;m constantly glued to DOpus now, because of Microsoft being strangely incapable of writing actually good software. And Microsoft loves to be the inclusion (note how i didn&#39;t say &amp;quot;the exception&amp;quot;) because a good portiojn of things I can name that they made? Terrible. Windows after Windows 7 is terrible. The File Explorer is terrible. The settings app is terrible. Storage Sense is terrible, even. Edge is terrible, new Edge is terrible. their website is terrible. I shouldn&#39;t have to support a company who has locked several people out of their Outlook accounts for no reason after buying it, randomly removing Minecraft from their accounts and even just making it overly difficult to recover your account when it&#39;s PG targetted. I refuse to use Edge for these reasons, and many many more. Just use another browser. &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft is an infamously terrible company and the last thing I&#39;m going to do is talk good about the dogshit they do. VSCode looks nice but doesn&#39;t excuse the stupid shit they love to do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Seamonkey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a quick fire round because I don&#39;t have much on Seamonkey, I quit it pretty fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, it was like very old Firefox that was bundled with a mailing client and a schedule thing I think. I stopped using it shortly after touching it because it was both pretty aged, and it&#39;s reaction to DRM was pretty finnicky. Wasn&#39;t ideal for my needs. May be a good experiment if you like Pale Moon though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also applies to similar Firefox forks like Basilisk and Pale Moon. They&#39;re great, but they&#39;re not really viable for daily driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Firefox: The Big One&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well well well, would you look at that. A browser run by a company &lt;a href=&quot;https://old.reddit.com/r/Piracy/comments/1f6ms0p/this_is_why_you_should_stop_suggesting_brave_to/ll2l16w/&quot;&gt;with a list of controversies as long as the geneva convention&lt;/a&gt;. Though we really don&#39;t have any chouce by now, so people started forking the SHIT out of this browser and now we have more sections to chose from. So we can distance from the controversial actions of this parent comany. Let&#39;s get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will likely be the longest part of this blog because I was always pretty interested in Firefox. Get some popcorn and get comfortable. :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Back Then&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://fossbytes.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Firefox-50.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Firefox 50 screenshot&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah boy, the firefox I&#39;m used to. This is Firefox 50, from about 2016. This is the real version of Firefox I&#39;m used to, this UI here. While there&#39;s older UIs that boomers will know way better, I&#39;m more used to this in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was before the &amp;quot;Quantum&amp;quot; overhaul, so naturally things are different here. Maybe I was scared of growing as a person and stuck to the classics. Maybe I just used it because I knew my dad used it a lot. Or maybe, just maybe, I was destined to prefer Firefox in the end. But something about Firefox always attracted me. I loved finding random Firefox themes like &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20170831124037/https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/midoriki/&quot; title=&quot;Redirects to an Internet Archive link of the theme.&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20170821014507/https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/aurora-australis/&quot; title=&quot;Redirects to an Internet Archive link of the theme.&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20170821151619/https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/stylus-red/&quot; title=&quot;Redirects to an Internet Archive link of the theme.&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20170821151619/https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/matrix-fox/&quot; title=&quot;Redirects to an Internet Archive link of the theme.&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20170821015424/https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/dark-fox-18066/&quot; title=&quot;Redirects to an Internet Archive link of the theme.&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20170821172150/https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/lightning-overload/&quot; title=&quot;Redirects to an Internet Archive link of the theme.&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20170821151453/https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/minecraft-grassy-block/&quot; title=&quot;Redirects to an Internet Archive link of the theme.&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; and- Oh, I got offtopic again. Whoops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Point is, I really loved Firefox. It looked really nice and it&#39;s themes really intruiged me when I was young. While this browser was unfortunately overshadowed by over browsers sometimes, Firefox still had that charm. Sure, I still believed that Adshower Plus was the only good solution to my needs, but it was still a great browser. A really great one. And I hold it pretty deep in my heart, even today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though, I still moved on, and wouldn&#39;t return to Firefox until way later. Because I was occiupied with Google Chrome and whatever else was before Waterfox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Later on&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the Quantum engine came out, which changed Firefox&#39;s UI and functionality to what it is today, to a degree. By this point, Chrome has just completely fucked up the market. I would end up returning to Firefox and having a pretty distasteful experience, and this goes in two parts, so listen closely and try not to misunderstand the story!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Old Attempt&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is before I became aware of Firefox hardening. I can already see somebody cringing as I say those words, I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, the browser was pretty bad. It was very slow and unpleasent. It seemed to be pretty busted and overall not fun to use. However, the thing was, I wasn&#39;t even using the browser properly, again, listen closely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The browser was not hardened, which impacted my experience. Specifically, a lot of the more demanding, useless features were still on. But the thing is, I didn&#39;t use a user.js file either! So not only did I change nothing, I didn&#39;t apply any optimizations. If you can see where this is bad, good for you!&lt;br&gt;
However since most of my audience is people who are out of the loop, I&#39;ll explain this to you quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User.js is a file in your Firefox profile folder that controls some browser settings. Why is this important? People have made custom user.js files which are known to be faster than Firefox&#39;s default settings. Why does this happen? We don&#39;t have a clue, ask the nerds. But the thing is, it&#39;s a little nerdy to install on just regular ol&#39; firefox. So I think you can imagine how it was not knowing about this feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I tried using the browser without literally any optimizations. As I got frustrated with Pocket&#39;s horrible news feed and a bunch of other things, I think you can imagine how fast I gave up. However, listen closely, there is another session we need to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Only Hardened&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, there it is. The better attempt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This attempt was a little better. I hardened the browser with &lt;a href=&quot;https://brainfucksec.github.io/firefox-hardening-guide&quot; title=&quot;Old version!&quot;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://brainfucksec.github.io/firefox-hardening-guide-2024&quot;&gt;(updated version)&lt;/a&gt; and for the most part, it was a little better! The browser started a little faster and was a little more effective than just running the whole thing raw, that was my last mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, listen again. Remember the user.js crap from before? I didn&#39;t run one on this session either! So again, the experience was pretty crap. Also, I think I broke it somehow later on, because according to my old notes, anything that uses Cloudflare was busted as shit. Also, roblox.com broke often, which, surprise, was an extension issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of extensions, let&#39;s clear the air fast. &lt;strong&gt;Firefox addons are not perfect.&lt;/strong&gt; In a lot of cases they&#39;re better (specifically Firefox actually having Sidebery), however they can tend to be buggier, or even not be there at all! There are some browsers later on that can mitigate this, however those are way later. But first we need to get under the right header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There we go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, Firefox is an... interesting case. I find that while ran completely vanilla, the experience was complete, and utter asshole. As expected. However, unlike Chromium, firefox is special. You see, it&#39;s forks are mostly preserved and some of them aren&#39;t even ass! You&#39;ll want to thank the community fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey speaking of, I happened to use a lot of forks lately. Let&#39;s go visit them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Librewolf&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, right off the bat, there is only VERY few use cases i recommend this browser since the changes it makes are wildly different from any other browser, so listen carefully!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s only recommended to use Librewolf if:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have no problem with being logged out of sites after each browser shutdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes, every browser shutdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&#39;t mind having to manually unbrick sites that may be bricked by certain privacy extensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(optionally) You absolutely care about your privacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I&#39;m serious. The paranoid type of behavior this browser is designed for is just plain insane. The amount of measures to protect you while you browse is just a bunch of layers upon layers. I get why this may appeal to some users, however, when I was looking for a daily driver, this kind of thing just wasn&#39;t for me. So I ended up continuing to look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if you&#39;ve been recently caring about your privacy or need a browser to clear your tracks when you close it, this browser is great for those kind of people, so feel free to download it and give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Waterfox&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waterfox was like a runnerup for me. Originally being built to provide x64 builds for better Firefox performance and later expanding it&#39;s horizons, Waterfox is like an extension of Firefox, run by different people. Now this might seem at first just like an obscure psuedo speedup of firefox or whatever you think it is, but Waterfox is pretty powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waterfox is very interesting because it&#39;s kind of like Floorp in a way. It has some interlopability with extensions, SPECIFICALLY tree style tabs, just like Floorp. However, Waterfox&#39;s implimentation just straight up connects the tabs to the Sidebar instead of using it like an extension. When you switch to the sidebar, the horizontial tabs are hidden, which is a small detail that&#39;s cool. I kind of miss it, but what can you say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, I did not use Waterfox with a user.js I think, so these are personal observations. But seemingly Waterfox seems to have some niche bugs. ListenBrainz fails to load album art sometimes, and it also mangled ROBLOX site loading times. It did also once brick the avatar editor pretty badly, although again, that might be an extension issue, I don&#39;t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, for some reason, Cloudflare authentication broke when I installed a custom CSS theme, so if a site needed me to do a Cloudflare captcha, I just couldn&#39;t do it! What the fuck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally though, this browser treated me pretty good despite these niche issues, and it was still surprisingly usable. It&#39;s a good alternative to Firefox if you just really hate Mozilla&#39;s guts like many people do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Where am I now?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we&#39;re about to enter the modern phase. Although, I want to quickly cross into an honorable mention, &lt;a href=&quot;https://thorium.rocks/&quot;&gt;Thorium&lt;/a&gt;, which is not firefox based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thorium, at it&#39;s core, is just Chromium on steroids. Many optimizations were applied over the browser and while it doesn&#39;t add anything special (except new toolbar buttons for experimental features), it&#39;s said to increase performance up to over 30% according to it&#39;s official page! That&#39;s impressive. While this browser does not fit my use cases since I&#39;m looking for an alternative, permanent anti-V3 Manifest ecosystem, if you still need to be on the Chrome Web Store ecosystem for some dumb ass reason, or you just really got attached to Google Chrome, Thorium is genuinely really cool and you should try it out fo a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ablaze Floorp&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, look. If you know how r/Browser tends to be, I might sound like a real glazer here. But just hear me out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Floorp is a fork of Firefox made in Japan, and I genuinely love what they&#39;ve done. Container tabs are integrated right in the thing, and Tree Style Tabs also has an option in settings. You can natively set tabs to sleep (it&#39;s called Sleeping Tabs) for any amount of time you want and set exceptions per URL. It also has the option to change your performance settings if you want to trade off some performance to save RAM and it also lets you pick a pre-made User JS to speed up your experience! God I love this fucking browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I went to install the same theme I did during Waterfox (FirefoxGX by the way), it broke things at first, but after merging one of the presets and the Firefox GX one (by copying the firefox gx user.js to the bottom of the one i installed), it worked like a magician trick and it was sweet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like Tree Style Tabs, you could also use Sidebery, which is similar, however it&#39;s support isn&#39;t baked into the browser. This won&#39;t stop you from hiding the Horizontial tabs and just using it anyway though, since it mostly works. Though you won&#39;t have Workspaces support like Floorp has, you can always just use the panels that Sidebery has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am actually in love with this browser. It&#39;s adapting for all of my recently picked up browsing habits, it&#39;s great. It fits my needs, it&#39;s faster than Firefox when run raw, and it supports all the same things. I have no reason to go back now and I can finally enjoy uBlock Origin without issue. At last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Ending Notes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that was a long week of writing. Thanks for dropping by! If you have any more questions or want to ask further about what I do, feel free to contact me and I&#39;ll see if I can help you.&lt;br&gt;
Go have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Switching from Spotify, foobar2000, and the many players out there</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2024/switching-from-spotify/" />
    <updated>2024-08-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2024/switching-from-spotify/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This blog post is intended for nerds but if you&#39;re not a nerd, you&#39;re also free to join some nerds in the circle! I am no professional at explaining anything under the sun, but we&#39;re going to try our best and make something sound sensible.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;When the pandemic started to die down around 2021, I learnt about and decided to switch to the long standing music player foobar2000 after learning about it through discord. I got the 32-bit version as it&#39;s all I saw, and immediately I got to work and started using the shit out of the player.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I would switch players often, as I always did. I had used AIMP and sometimes WinAmp the year prior, having used those all my life. I did also find myself interested in the windows bundled app windows media player 12 (as included with windows 7 and up, now unfortunately replaced with whatever wmp11 is) for all of those windows addicts and fruitiger aero people, but as cool as the player was, it wasn&#39;t practical. So I had to turn elsewhere.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;First, let&#39;s tackle the elephant in the room, and the one everybody&#39;s going to get Nostalgic over. I hate to ruin everybody&#39;s fun but I do have a few things to say. Windows Media Player 12, first bundled with Windows 7, and continued to be bundled with Windows up until late versions of Windows 11, when it was replaced. &lt;br&gt;We&#39;ll drift into positives first: Simplicity. WMP12 made it very simple to handle audio, it was my first exposure to auto-scaling media library features and even my first exposure to genre tags and file tagging as a whole. I had lots of fun messing with it, learning the ins and outs, even messing around with the feature that would fix album art for songs that had it missing. It was a blast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then I grew up. I realized how much easier it was to fight with the player as I got older, how features begun to break and how I was no longer enjoying the player, and moreso fighting with it for control. Album art fetching broke, I started to fight with the tag system, I became unsatisfied. And then I left. Remembering how I would sometimes use AIMP on the side, I hopped ships.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AIMP was all fun, but it got boring fast. It had a nice UI and the plugins were awesome! The wallpapers would be nice additions too, especially the older 2009 wallpapers. But it always felt there was something missing sometimes, it played and did what it was meant to, but something left me wanting more.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;WinAmp seemed to fill that hole for a while longer. Even though I used it later than I did AIMP, around ~2020, it had felt like a more old-school version of AIMP, which is probably where the UI design choices from AIMP came from. It also had the iconic Milkdrop visualizer and whatever else was popular with people, something I enjoyed heavily. However when looking between AIMP and WinAmp, they were almost the same thing to me. On top of that, Spotify looked a little nicer, and WinAmp, it felt off. Spotify was a different beast, which we&#39;ll have to get to in a minute.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Then it kind of crashed down. Apparently WinAmp had not been the same since it&#39;s glory days, the last widely favored release being 5.666. But I was using a version later than that. So the real question was, what now?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I tried more players, tried returning to childhood favorites. Tried SoundCloud and found it&#39;s selection kind of mediocre, only good for a few songs at best. I became briefly obsessed with obscure players, sometimes going to bizzare lengths to try new setups. But nothing was entirely satisfying. So instead, I just stuck with what I knew and waited for life to throw a bone. I transitioned from YouTube downloading my music to using ThePirateBay torrents and took my loss.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We are going to briefly skip ahead, to 2023. That was the day I learnt about WinAmp&#39;s downfall, and their transition to v6, which was distasteful and very boring to me. Plus they had briefly tried to go into NFTs apparently, trying to sell of the OG WinAmp UI as an NFT. That was dumb and I didn&#39;t get any of it.&lt;br&gt;But looming over it was like a hand from the heavens, coming to bring me a refresher, something new. Sure, it was pretty much WinAmp, but it was something better. Something that was separated from the original company.&lt;br&gt;WACUP.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;So then I tried WACUP. I recognized all the same things, but at the time, I was so distant from WinAmp, that everything was new enough to enjoy. It added more things to WinAmp, it had more things to enjoy, more optimizations and the like. And being run by who I think was one of the original WinAmp developers, it was a win. But once again, comparing to AIMP, they felt very similar in many aspects, and once again, I felt myself wanting more.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And now we have to talk about big brother. Spotify. Let&#39;s go back to 2018.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I turned to Spotify during the summer of that year, somewhere around 2 years after first being obsessed with WMP12. The convenience appealed to me, and while I wouldn&#39;t get to enjoy some of the exclusives I loved when I was in the AIMP/WMP12 era, but at the time it was a sacrifice I was willing to make. I skipped out on my favorites that were limited to the Japan editions and whatnot, but it was a sacrifice I wanted to make for convenience.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And so I did. For about 2 more years, I stuck with Spotify, only occasionally switching away from Spotify when I started to grow a hate for it&#39;s Local Files feature just to use a music player. And I was happy for the most part, kind of just taking hit after hit from Spotify over the years. I put up with the video ads, I put up with the audio ads, I gave in to the ads just to have convenience in my life, in a time where I didn&#39;t know that there was better options. I only briefly knew the history of platforms like Limewire then, I didn&#39;t know what I was doing. So I turned to the popular option. Hoping for some kind of help.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And over the years, it was finally unlocked in me. For two years, I took hit after hit, continuing to stick with Spotify. When using Discord, I kept using Spotify for rich presence, not knowing about the other options once again. My option was set in stone, cold as ice. I never turned back permanently, Spotify has locked me in.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;That&#39;s what it had looked like. Slowly, the plugs would be pulled. I would finally turn to a music player and start to enjoy that more than Spotify. And coincidentally, all the right plugs would also be pulled on many features. The support for the original December 2013-2014 clients that Spotify used to have would break, it&#39;s functionality would eventually die out. Many songs would be taken down over the years, including various songs that I listened to often, and when those were out of the picture, the rope was put very thin. Spotify would also kill some of it&#39;s API which would also break functionalities in some players outside of Spotify, preventing them from streaming audio from Spotify even if you had Premium. And now more recently, Lyrics were killed. I had enough. I left Spotify, and while I would return a few more times to give it a second chance, it wouldn&#39;t always do the trick. I still wanted more.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I would try a few more players, and even briefly become attached to the similar player MusicBee. MusicBee would end up also being briefly good, but then I would find I wanted more features, once again. MB was great but it didn&#39;t have entirely what I was looking for. So then I set eyes on foobar2000, my next choice. The round killer.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;At first, foobar2000 was kind of just any other player for me. I would use it on and off between ~2020 and 2023, mainly going between foobar2000 and MusicBee. I would miss the features of the player I wasn&#39;t using, make the hop, then feel it all again. I missed foobar2000&#39;s simplicity. I missed MusicBee&#39;s discord plugin. I missed foobar2000&#39;s component ecosystem. I missed MusicBee&#39;s rating feature. It would go on and on. It would be like a nonstop battle for about three years.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And that brings me to around September 2023. After some extensive modding of foobar2000, I would eventually get the player in a pretty good state. And by that point, it was too late for me to switch. I was so invested in the things you could do with foobar2000, I was just hooked. You could change anything. You could add new buttons next to the pause and skip and backwards buttons, you could add new functionality. I played around with everything, from adding viewable lyrics to the player, to AIMP bookmarking, A-B loop, Discord Rich Presence, waveform minibar, YouTube playback... The list goes on.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The idea of components would come and go, I would grow very satisfied. I would change my layout often, trying to get new ideas, and I would expand my taste by researching and adding features from other players I liked. I eventually also added artwork to the playlist view, a change I stuck with since. Overall, my listening experience was just better.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I would also learn about ReplayGain this way, as well as the various formats outside of MP3. FLAC was finally known to me. I got to experiment with OGG and learn about the OPUS format. I also finally got a very basic idea about how music rips were made, even learning to make my own, learning to keep a local collection of music that would never be pulled as long as I kept it untampered as long as possible. It was like a personal haven.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And that brings us to today.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For the past year, I have been using the 64-bit version of foobar2000, mainly for the performance benefits. It&#39;s new, futureproof, I was sold on the illusion that it would just perform better, and for a while I had no requirements that required me to go back, at least for a while.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;That was until now, obviously. I was growing rather bored of the current hacky, very rough solution for my problem. It was not only very rough and buggy, I had broken folders in folders on my own accord and I just wanted it to be hassle free. So I decided to pick myself up and turned to the 32-bit side again, having become interested in Spider Monkey Panel, which was an updated version of a foobar2000 component that allowed adding JS to the player. Without a second thought, I kicked the door down and walked right into the land this morning, to play around and find new adventures.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I had originally planned to return to my original solution, however after hearing the great things about SMPanel, I gave it a try. And I was pleasantly amazed, after some setup and some hammering of my own. It had in fact worked how I hoped it would, and more! It was not perfect obviously, but it was less fragile than my original implementation. Bit by bit, I got it configured to my needs and I had finally made it home to the player that I wanted so much.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The only thing that made me downgrade from x64 to x32 is the current state of foobar2000 components. Currently, the world has been split into two. There are the legacy 32-bit components that everybody else is desperately clinged onto, and the 64-bit lands, that is future-proof in case the technology industry pulls the plug. Somehow we are still alive, but the thing is, many legacy components won&#39;t update to also support x64. Some components go back to the early 2010s and even the late 2000s! Sure, that makes a good history lesson, and that admittedly turns us into a history channel, but the thing is not everybody wants history. Some people just want to update to x64 thinking they need it, or thinking x32 doesn&#39;t work. So then what do we do?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We just have to wait. SMP won&#39;t update to x64 for a while, that would require SMP v2 to be finished, and we got at least a few more years. So I guess I&#39;m going to be stuck here, on x32. Where everybody&#39;s happy and nostalgic.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;At least it&#39;s better than not having it at all, right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks for coming to my Ted Talk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You are excused.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Games - A Bloody Downgrade</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2024/the-games-rant/" />
    <updated>2024-08-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2024/the-games-rant/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;First post here, it&#39;s a sequel to a rant to another ROBLOX event I&#39;ve talked about before with my heart.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Update: Added a tiny bit more information following The Games, as I felt I didn&#39;t add enough when writing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just want to clear up where my research is from first, because it&#39;s best if you look into this yourself before reading my yap and coming to your own conclusions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vfa0w33_T14&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Chizeled&#39;s video is a good place to start.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;As I&#39;m writing this, it only came out like an hour ago! I used it to double check some research such as with the &quot;pay to win&quot; items, some points, etc. Watch it if you wanna learn more!&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77EdrxzLb2M&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;This greenlegocats video will explain the Live Ops and Boys and Girls Dance Club thing a little better.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Yes, it actually happened. Start watching at 10:45 and see for yourself.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.roblox.com/games/17427651911/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Play the event yourself too!!!&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;I got most of my game claims from the games themselves, and tried to include screenshots if I remembered.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1&gt;History&#39;s Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;Okay, so what makes a normal ROBLOX event fun? Well, they should last maybe a month, they should have a good selection of games, and you shouldn&#39;t be left confused and lost. The more memorable the event the better, but normally that doesn&#39;t make a difference.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Now, The Hunt: First Edition? It at least made an attempt, but it overwhelmed people with it&#39;s 100 games, did easter events in a style people found lazy (&quot;dev hunts&quot;), most of the items ended up being really expensive and event exclusive, and there was very little free prizes among other things. Despite those issues, The Hunt was a return to ROBLOX events and while it had many flaws, some that completely ruined the event, it still had potential and needed some serious feedback to be improved.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And The Classic?&lt;br&gt;Worse than the last event (subjectively). Hear me out.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Crunched for Time&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;Let&#39;s address the elephant in the room: The Classic just doesn&#39;t give you enough time to really grind at your own comfortable pace. It has better compacting sure, and has less games, but the amount of items is still the same! And you&#39;ll have to play the same game several times! Not only in a way that&#39;s possibly unfair (i.e: completing a whole minigame with crap teammates, super high difficulty etc), but also you only get a week to do it! Why put in effort when there is no effort? That&#39;s why I tried it for a few hours, then didn&#39;t bother. The grind wasn&#39;t even worth it. Lazy of me, sure, but wouldn&#39;t that make ROBLOX just as lazy of a company for making this garbage? We gave lots of feedback, did they not listen to all of it?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I get that the timeframe celebrates history and it&#39;s the time between the site&#39;s reaction and trademarks being made, but that&#39;s only 5 days. Nobody&#39;s going to stomach this entire event in five days! At least, I&#39;m not...&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s also add on the fact most people will be busy with school and work and whatnot. So not only is it too short by regular standards, you leave basically no time for anybody who&#39;s actually studying right now! If this isn&#39;t the shortsighted part of the event...&lt;br&gt;ROBLOX. You are a KIDS game. If the KIDS are busy studying, why would you engineer this event during this time? THINK.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Not only that, but it also has the same issues as the last event. Most of the good items that were showcased were either pay high amounts to get, or they ended up being extremely tedious to get. Not only that, but there&#39;s the same amount of items spread across each game: You can still only get one measly item every few days, and there&#39;s still only 5 total. So there&#39;s very little to earn without paying, too much to earn by paying. The only real improvement in that area is that they removed the Robux tiers. Even then, they did Tix VERY dirty by making it buy items you can only use in the lobby. The fuck? I don&#39;t wanna use a rocket launcher in just one single game, what is this?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The main prizes aren&#39;t even that good. The first item makes no fucking sense to me, the fuck is this? A wrap for my arms? It surely doesn&#39;t look like a Tixsplosion reskin. Other than that, I will say that there&#39;s accuracy in some of the items, to some degree. There&#39;s a buckethead, a helm, and that one hat that gives you wings and a halo. Personally a step up from the ugly and hardly fitting items from last time. Now, that&#39;s a huge improvement, but unfortunately still-&lt;br&gt;What? They&#39;re making avatar items more expensive AGAIN? Nope, that sounds like modern ROBLOX.&lt;br&gt;Oh, even better, you added back the items you have to pay robux for? And they&#39;re still identical to the main items except in gold? Great, what a wonderful event!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Let&#39;s continue to the event itself now.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Inconsistencies, Ahoy!&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;Now, I am not by any means an older player. Depending on who you ask, either I&#39;m older than most of ROBLOX&#39;s active playerbase, or I&#39;m not even close to being an &#39;older&#39; player. But just hear me out.&lt;br&gt;I think ROBLOX is &lt;b&gt;not &lt;/b&gt;properly doing the classic theme. Let me explain.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Since many active people played past 2016, let&#39;s start with the things you&#39;re more likely to notice:&lt;br&gt;First off, the UI takes modern design hints. The mute music button uses an emoji, and is placed by the modern icons. Now that would be cool in any other game, but this is a classic themed event. You couldn&#39;t have hand drawn an icon? What about doing it how old games did and using the text &quot;Mute Music&quot;? At the least, using old color schemes, like 2013+&#39;s blue and grey, or even 2012&#39;s red and black?&lt;br&gt;Less noticably, dialogs and chat. While dialog textures the same as they were in 2015 and later on, they still use 2022+ chat bubbles. The opposite also applies to chat, how the chat box is the modern chat box, but they could of used the old chat box, WHICH BY THE WAY, IS STILL SUPPORTED.&lt;br&gt;I can only assume this was likely a corporate decision. I could say a bunch of reasons why this happened, such as corporate greed, or just a dev team who had no idea about ROBLOX&#39;s 18 year history... Holy shit, it&#39;s going to have been 18 years in September.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Anyway, there&#39;s also safe chat. Of course, they didn&#39;t remove chat for people younger than 13... That would be dumb. But they added that little chat bubble from 2008 where you click options and there&#39;s buttons... That thing. But they don&#39;t have most of the old dialogs, so it feels more like it&#39;s there for novelty rather than accuracy. But at least we have old games featured...&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Not Even Classic!&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;Oh sorry, is this event called The Classic? Are we meant to have some old selection, and are we gonna get an event related to oldschool games? Nope, you DON&#39;T. They hyped the event up by listing actually old games like Crossroads and Natural Disaster Survival, but then jinxed it by making nearly none of the games classic. Not to mention, Toilet Tower Defense of all games being in this list is a good example. It can be argued that Adopt Me and Arsenal earned their slots, sure. But Blade Ball? A last event&#39;s game, Driving Empire? Dress to Impress? Fucking a dusty road trip? Hell, there&#39;s even games here from First Edition! Was it hard to get new games?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Speaking of, the version of A Dusty Road Trip featured is supposedly, a ripoff. It&#39;s a clone of a similar game, just with a bunch of added gamepasses to make some quick bucks. Basically most modern games on the site nowadays. Hell, what if I told you this wasn&#39;t the first time? About 2019, they replaced ROBLOX events with this thing called &quot;Live Ops&quot;, which you might recognize instead as &quot;This Week on ROBLOX&quot;. Did you know the version of Boys and Girls Dance Club featured was stolen? And it wasn&#39;t taken down for a good while too, it got featured for a good few weeks! Great management, ROBLOX.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It probably also doesn&#39;t help that this game is also hell to wrap your head around. Just like the first edition, Adopt Me doesn&#39;t seem to have a clear cut button for the event. Arsenal, unlike last event, doesn&#39;t have one either. Gunfight Arena has a completely unrelated task you have to do before you can even DO the event stuff that gets you what you want. We&#39;re suffering! Is that not enough?&lt;br&gt;It&#39;s already a lot that most of these games don&#39;t follow the old theming, even for new generation games, although that&#39;s to be expected at this point. At least Dress to Impress used squared brick textures and tried to make something! The only real relation Bedwars had to old roblox was the penguins held fucking swords and cokes! Is that the best we get as players? Is there no regulation about using old models and trying to use as little modern models as possible?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://files.catbox.moe/0mtv1v.png&quot; alt=&quot;Modern model among the old road. Game is A Dusty Road Trip.&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like what the fuck is this? This looks ugly. You have this modern bag model, and it&#39;s on an oldschool road, and all of this oldschool text. It looks so out of place. Arguably our avatars are too, but at least there&#39;s a toggle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Better yet, even the playerbase has some (cheap, although functional) options to fit in with the classic part of this event. Many choose not to, which only beats the dead horse on this event, but there&#39;s at least immersion. The player can CHOOSE to come with a classic avatar to feel more immersed. This game doesn&#39;t even bother to immerse you.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Rich people, ahoy!&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;Did you not get enough of this event? You wanna blow your money? You like expensive things? 19k Valkrie bundle, go get it. So great, isn&#39;t it? Great to get fucked over like this? There&#39;s even one for a fedora, named the &quot;Treasure Hunter&quot;... What am I hunting again? I don&#39;t feel like I&#39;m hunting, I feel more like I&#39;m doing chores in the house.&lt;br&gt;Great to spend money to get gold variants of a bunch of shit you won&#39;t use in the end? Yeah, me too.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;They did this last event too. Make a bunch of gold variants of the items, make it exclusive to either a 800 Robux gold lineup, a 19k bundle that was limited time, or you can pay it for one item out of pocket. This shit was just one fucked up cash grab, and we all got deep in it. Deep ini the chores list, sure.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;But what&#39;s the point in the end? Why are we spending so much? Well, because ROBLOX wants to make MONEY! That&#39;s the only way I can assume this event was so bad, that the last event was so rushed, that all of the events before it... Just cheap tricks.&lt;br&gt;Because we aren&#39;t getting old events anymore. That&#39;s obvious.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;What Else?&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;Other than that though, that&#39;s where it ends. I didn&#39;t bother to play much in my, what, 3 hours of playing? In Bedwars I got killed by the void, even though the pixels clearly said I died to a penguin. A dusty trip had a vip room, which apparently has a free tshirt to check what&#39;s inside! I didn&#39;t look yet, I&#39;m too lazy to continue this dogshit event.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I got into lobbies with lots of noobs on Bedwars and Bee Swarm Simulator. Livetopia has confusing store layouts, and that task is long and tedious. Feels more like a chore. Arsenal was unclear with how you get the quest done, unlike First Edition. Hell, first edition had a whole singleplayer experience! Why didn&#39;t we get something like that again?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;That&#39;s a... lot to work with. Wow, this event is just as bad as The First Edition.&lt;br&gt;I wrote double than I did my last ROBLOX event rant, and that one was also made with a lot of care.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Well... I guess that&#39;s it.&lt;br&gt;Surely they can&#39;t fuck up three times?</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Classic - A repeat of the past</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2024/the-classic-rant/" />
    <updated>2024-05-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2024/the-classic-rant/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;First post here, it&#39;s a sequel to a rant to another ROBLOX event I&#39;ve talked about before with my heart.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Update: Added a tiny bit more information following The Games, as I felt I didn&#39;t add enough when writing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just want to clear up where my research is from first, because it&#39;s best if you look into this yourself before reading my yap and coming to your own conclusions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vfa0w33_T14&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Chizeled&#39;s video is a good place to start.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;As I&#39;m writing this, it only came out like an hour ago! I used it to double check some research such as with the &quot;pay to win&quot; items, some points, etc. Watch it if you wanna learn more!&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77EdrxzLb2M&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;This greenlegocats video will explain the Live Ops and Boys and Girls Dance Club thing a little better.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Yes, it actually happened. Start watching at 10:45 and see for yourself.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.roblox.com/games/17427651911/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Play the event yourself too!!!&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;I got most of my game claims from the games themselves, and tried to include screenshots if I remembered.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1&gt;History&#39;s Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;Okay, so what makes a normal ROBLOX event fun? Well, they should last maybe a month, they should have a good selection of games, and you shouldn&#39;t be left confused and lost. The more memorable the event the better, but normally that doesn&#39;t make a difference.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Now, The Hunt: First Edition? It at least made an attempt, but it overwhelmed people with it&#39;s 100 games, did easter events in a style people found lazy (&quot;dev hunts&quot;), most of the items ended up being really expensive and event exclusive, and there was very little free prizes among other things. Despite those issues, The Hunt was a return to ROBLOX events and while it had many flaws, some that completely ruined the event, it still had potential and needed some serious feedback to be improved.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And The Classic?&lt;br&gt;Worse than the last event (subjectively). Hear me out.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Crunched for Time&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;Let&#39;s address the elephant in the room: The Classic just doesn&#39;t give you enough time to really grind at your own comfortable pace. It has better compacting sure, and has less games, but the amount of items is still the same! And you&#39;ll have to play the same game several times! Not only in a way that&#39;s possibly unfair (i.e: completing a whole minigame with crap teammates, super high difficulty etc), but also you only get a week to do it! Why put in effort when there is no effort? That&#39;s why I tried it for a few hours, then didn&#39;t bother. The grind wasn&#39;t even worth it. Lazy of me, sure, but wouldn&#39;t that make ROBLOX just as lazy of a company for making this garbage? We gave lots of feedback, did they not listen to all of it?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I get that the timeframe celebrates history and it&#39;s the time between the site&#39;s reaction and trademarks being made, but that&#39;s only 5 days. Nobody&#39;s going to stomach this entire event in five days! At least, I&#39;m not...&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s also add on the fact most people will be busy with school and work and whatnot. So not only is it too short by regular standards, you leave basically no time for anybody who&#39;s actually studying right now! If this isn&#39;t the shortsighted part of the event...&lt;br&gt;ROBLOX. You are a KIDS game. If the KIDS are busy studying, why would you engineer this event during this time? THINK.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Not only that, but it also has the same issues as the last event. Most of the good items that were showcased were either pay high amounts to get, or they ended up being extremely tedious to get. Not only that, but there&#39;s the same amount of items spread across each game: You can still only get one measly item every few days, and there&#39;s still only 5 total. So there&#39;s very little to earn without paying, too much to earn by paying. The only real improvement in that area is that they removed the Robux tiers. Even then, they did Tix VERY dirty by making it buy items you can only use in the lobby. The fuck? I don&#39;t wanna use a rocket launcher in just one single game, what is this?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The main prizes aren&#39;t even that good. The first item makes no fucking sense to me, the fuck is this? A wrap for my arms? It surely doesn&#39;t look like a Tixsplosion reskin. Other than that, I will say that there&#39;s accuracy in some of the items, to some degree. There&#39;s a buckethead, a helm, and that one hat that gives you wings and a halo. Personally a step up from the ugly and hardly fitting items from last time. Now, that&#39;s a huge improvement, but unfortunately still-&lt;br&gt;What? They&#39;re making avatar items more expensive AGAIN? Nope, that sounds like modern ROBLOX.&lt;br&gt;Oh, even better, you added back the items you have to pay robux for? And they&#39;re still identical to the main items except in gold? Great, what a wonderful event!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Let&#39;s continue to the event itself now.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Inconsistencies, Ahoy!&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;Now, I am not by any means an older player. Depending on who you ask, either I&#39;m older than most of ROBLOX&#39;s active playerbase, or I&#39;m not even close to being an &#39;older&#39; player. But just hear me out.&lt;br&gt;I think ROBLOX is &lt;b&gt;not &lt;/b&gt;properly doing the classic theme. Let me explain.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Since many active people played past 2016, let&#39;s start with the things you&#39;re more likely to notice:&lt;br&gt;First off, the UI takes modern design hints. The mute music button uses an emoji, and is placed by the modern icons. Now that would be cool in any other game, but this is a classic themed event. You couldn&#39;t have hand drawn an icon? What about doing it how old games did and using the text &quot;Mute Music&quot;? At the least, using old color schemes, like 2013+&#39;s blue and grey, or even 2012&#39;s red and black?&lt;br&gt;Less noticably, dialogs and chat. While dialog textures the same as they were in 2015 and later on, they still use 2022+ chat bubbles. The opposite also applies to chat, how the chat box is the modern chat box, but they could of used the old chat box, WHICH BY THE WAY, IS STILL SUPPORTED.&lt;br&gt;I can only assume this was likely a corporate decision. I could say a bunch of reasons why this happened, such as corporate greed, or just a dev team who had no idea about ROBLOX&#39;s 18 year history... Holy shit, it&#39;s going to have been 18 years in September.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Anyway, there&#39;s also safe chat. Of course, they didn&#39;t remove chat for people younger than 13... That would be dumb. But they added that little chat bubble from 2008 where you click options and there&#39;s buttons... That thing. But they don&#39;t have most of the old dialogs, so it feels more like it&#39;s there for novelty rather than accuracy. But at least we have old games featured...&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Not Even Classic!&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;Oh sorry, is this event called The Classic? Are we meant to have some old selection, and are we gonna get an event related to oldschool games? Nope, you DON&#39;T. They hyped the event up by listing actually old games like Crossroads and Natural Disaster Survival, but then jinxed it by making nearly none of the games classic. Not to mention, Toilet Tower Defense of all games being in this list is a good example. It can be argued that Adopt Me and Arsenal earned their slots, sure. But Blade Ball? A last event&#39;s game, Driving Empire? Dress to Impress? Fucking a dusty road trip? Hell, there&#39;s even games here from First Edition! Was it hard to get new games?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Speaking of, the version of A Dusty Road Trip featured is supposedly, a ripoff. It&#39;s a clone of a similar game, just with a bunch of added gamepasses to make some quick bucks. Basically most modern games on the site nowadays. Hell, what if I told you this wasn&#39;t the first time? About 2019, they replaced ROBLOX events with this thing called &quot;Live Ops&quot;, which you might recognize instead as &quot;This Week on ROBLOX&quot;. Did you know the version of Boys and Girls Dance Club featured was stolen? And it wasn&#39;t taken down for a good while too, it got featured for a good few weeks! Great management, ROBLOX.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It probably also doesn&#39;t help that this game is also hell to wrap your head around. Just like the first edition, Adopt Me doesn&#39;t seem to have a clear cut button for the event. Arsenal, unlike last event, doesn&#39;t have one either. Gunfight Arena has a completely unrelated task you have to do before you can even DO the event stuff that gets you what you want. We&#39;re suffering! Is that not enough?&lt;br&gt;It&#39;s already a lot that most of these games don&#39;t follow the old theming, even for new generation games, although that&#39;s to be expected at this point. At least Dress to Impress used squared brick textures and tried to make something! The only real relation Bedwars had to old roblox was the penguins held fucking swords and cokes! Is that the best we get as players? Is there no regulation about using old models and trying to use as little modern models as possible?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://files.catbox.moe/0mtv1v.png&quot; alt=&quot;Modern model among the old road. Game is A Dusty Road Trip.&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like what the fuck is this? This looks ugly. You have this modern bag model, and it&#39;s on an oldschool road, and all of this oldschool text. It looks so out of place. Arguably our avatars are too, but at least there&#39;s a toggle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Better yet, even the playerbase has some (cheap, although functional) options to fit in with the classic part of this event. Many choose not to, which only beats the dead horse on this event, but there&#39;s at least immersion. The player can CHOOSE to come with a classic avatar to feel more immersed. This game doesn&#39;t even bother to immerse you.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Rich people, ahoy!&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;Did you not get enough of this event? You wanna blow your money? You like expensive things? 19k Valkrie bundle, go get it. So great, isn&#39;t it? Great to get fucked over like this? There&#39;s even one for a fedora, named the &quot;Treasure Hunter&quot;... What am I hunting again? I don&#39;t feel like I&#39;m hunting, I feel more like I&#39;m doing chores in the house.&lt;br&gt;Great to spend money to get gold variants of a bunch of shit you won&#39;t use in the end? Yeah, me too.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;They did this last event too. Make a bunch of gold variants of the items, make it exclusive to either a 800 Robux gold lineup, a 19k bundle that was limited time, or you can pay it for one item out of pocket. This shit was just one fucked up cash grab, and we all got deep in it. Deep ini the chores list, sure.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;But what&#39;s the point in the end? Why are we spending so much? Well, because ROBLOX wants to make MONEY! That&#39;s the only way I can assume this event was so bad, that the last event was so rushed, that all of the events before it... Just cheap tricks.&lt;br&gt;Because we aren&#39;t getting old events anymore. That&#39;s obvious.&lt;br&gt;&lt;h1&gt;What Else?&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;br&gt;Other than that though, that&#39;s where it ends. I didn&#39;t bother to play much in my, what, 3 hours of playing? In Bedwars I got killed by the void, even though the pixels clearly said I died to a penguin. A dusty trip had a vip room, which apparently has a free tshirt to check what&#39;s inside! I didn&#39;t look yet, I&#39;m too lazy to continue this dogshit event.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I got into lobbies with lots of noobs on Bedwars and Bee Swarm Simulator. Livetopia has confusing store layouts, and that task is long and tedious. Feels more like a chore. Arsenal was unclear with how you get the quest done, unlike First Edition. Hell, first edition had a whole singleplayer experience! Why didn&#39;t we get something like that again?&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;That&#39;s a... lot to work with. Wow, this event is just as bad as The First Edition.&lt;br&gt;I wrote double than I did my last ROBLOX event rant, and that one was also made with a lot of care.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Well... I guess that&#39;s it.&lt;br&gt;Surely they can&#39;t fuck up three times?</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Are Flash Games long gone?</title>
    <link href="https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2023/flash-games-retrospective/" />
    <updated>2023-03-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://aprilhvs.neocities.org/blog/posts/2023/flash-games-retrospective/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ah, Adobe Flash.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you were lucky enough to have a computer (or at least have access to one for more than 5 minutes) in the past 10 to 20 years, you&#39;ve probably heard of the wonderful world of browser games. Whenever it&#39;s actually Flash, or something like HTML5, maybe you somehow found a game made in Shockwave (i don&#39;t think i have), something else?&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve actually used technology in that timeframe, you&#39;ve most likely played a game like that at some point. I know I have, always getting on Silver Games or Andkon Arcade. Sometimes I&#39;d try an actual site directly, like Armor Games. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It was just a fun time then. It was fun to get on, play the dumbest shit you could find, and go goof off. I could probably name a lot of games I faintly remember playing but can&#39;t find anymore. One of those was this kind of Bomberman series with I think more than 5 games, somewhere like that? I don&#39;t remember much ughh, I wish I did. I was also the type to play Minecraft-themed shit, obviously. I think there was this one game called Guildcraft, it was a clicker which was boring, but you actually had to buy items together to click faster, and you could only unlock some items if you bought others, kind of keeps it like how Minecraft&#39;s crafting system was, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I feel like now I&#39;m just rambling to myself, but flash games were a fun time. You had the best shit, the worst shit, and the weird shit. Whenever you were at school, goofing off at home, or just needed to do something while waiting for that super cool event, you could pick up a flash game and play.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Now it feels moreso like a novelty. Or a one way ticket into nostalgia. Obviously, anything outdated is bound to do that, I mean why else are we using SpaceHey instead of modern Myspace? Yuck. But the thing is, SpaceHey is just a recreation of something that existed. Flash is something that&#39;s actually dead, yet still kind of works with the original software. It&#39;s weird, it&#39;s kind of like the feeling you get when you use MSN Messenger in modern day. Yes, that&#39;s a thing, and it&#39;s cool.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Sometimes, it feels like people have moved on from Adobe Flash, as if the games made in it don&#39;t exist anymore. Obviously, I&#39;m not saying all flash games are gone forever because of Flash&#39;s death. I mean, we did get a Henry Stickmin game on Steam, after all. We also have the Fancy Pants Adventure games (that&#39;s the right game, right?) on Steam too. We also have Mutiliate a Doll 2, if you remember that (props to those who do, loved that and Interactive Buddy!), although People Playground is more popular, which is basically the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Regardless, I&#39;m saying we&#39;ve moved on from Flash easily. Our memories of playing Flash is just a dead memory to us now, and we&#39;ve moved on. Which, is obviously a part of growing up, but doesn&#39;t it feel unfair to not at least visit back every once and a while, and think back on the goofy games we used to play then?&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>